派拉蒙影业巨献
赤色分子
导演:沃伦・比蒂
主演:黛安・基顿
爱德华・赫尔曼
杰兹・库辛斯基
杰克・尼科尔森
保罗・索尔维诺
莫林・斯特普尔顿
好像是1913还是1917年 记不太清楚了
Was that in 1913 or 17? I can't remember now.
我开始忘记所有过去认识的人
I'm beginning to forget all the people that I used to know, see?
你问我记得路易丝・拜伦吗？
Do I remember Louise Bryant?
当然记得，即便想忘也忘不了
Why, of course. I couldn't forget her if I tried.
我无法…
I can't...
我也许可以抹去我的记忆
I might sort of scratch my memory,
但那个时刻无法忘却
but not at the moment.
往事如烟，来了又去
You know, things go and come back again.
那是在克里斯托弗街
It was Christopher Street,
我当时在想…
and I was thinking about
另外一条街道
another street down there instead,
直到又回想起是克里斯托弗街
until it came back that it was Christopher Street.
有时我也会有失误
Sometimes I have lapses like that.
我已经把他们全忘记了
I'd forgotten all about them.
他们是社会主义者？
Were they socialists?
他们一定是
I guess they must've been,
但我想他们根本不重要
but I don't think they were of any importance.
我完全记不起他们了
I don't remember them at all.
我知道杰克和玛宝・道吉交往过
I know that Jack went around with Mabel Dodge,
后来他和另一个女孩交往
and then he went around with another gal,
接着就是和路易丝・拜伦
and then he went around with Louise Bryant.
来来回回换了好几轮
I know there were shifts back and forth,
但我从没发生过这种事
but it never occurred to me...
它侵犯不了我的个人生活
It never impinged on my own personal life.
我喜欢棒球
I like baseball.
我不知道外面世界的人 是如何看待他们的
I don't know what the outside world thought of them.
但他们曾经是夫妻
But they were a couple.
人们总会说起 路易丝拜伦和杰克・雷德
I mean, you always spoke of Louise Bryant and Jack Reed.
我记得他跟我说过他上大学时…
I recall his telling me that he had two ambitions
有两个远大理想
when he came to college.
其中一个就是当选班长
One was to be elected president of his class.
他并不认识班上的同学，也没人认识他
He didn't know anyone in the class. No one knew him.
另外一个就是在他25岁时…
The other was to make a million dollars
成为百万富翁
by the time he was 25.
我对于杰克・雷德的看法 可能不同于大多数人
Now, my idea about Jack Reed is probably different from most.
但我非常了解他 我知道他是个很有见地的人
But I knew him well. I knew he was a man of strong views.
我知道他非常的独立
I knew he was independent.
我有个看法，可能是错的…
And I have an idea, I may be wrong of this,
那就是他的妻子是个社会主义者
that his wife was a Communist
妻子影响了他，和任何人的妻子一样
and that his wife had influenced him, as any wife does,
这点大家和我都知道
as you know and I know.
路易丝拜伦？
Louise Bryant?
我曾认为她是个裸露狂
Well, I thought she was something of an exhibitionist.
不，我不是说人闲话，不要自欺欺人
No, I'm not gonna talk about people. Don't fool yourself.
不，先生，我不是…
No, sir. I'm not... I'm not
那种喜欢说三道四的街坊
a purveyor of neighborhood gossip, or anything of the kind.
那不是我的工作
That's not my job.
他沉默寡言
He was quiet.
是个好人
He was a nice fellow.
如果我遇到他，我会说他是个好人
I would say, if I met him, I would say he was a nice fellow.
按照特定的标准…
He was, however, a fighting fellow
他是个好战的人
in regards to principles.
我说过，一个对世界状况…
I said, I think, that a guy who's always interested
感兴趣并想改变它的人…
in the condition of the world and changing it
自己对于拒绝或直面它…
either has no problems of his own
不会有任何问题
or refuses to face them.
杰克，我不认为他是个花花公子
Jack... Well, I wouldn't call him a playboy,
但有人这么认为
but some people did.
杰克・雷德的人生短暂
Jack Reed's life, short as it was,
如同昙花一现
happened at a time,
我们所有人都是那个时代的受害者
and all of us, after all, are the victims of our time and place,
作为一个记者 他本来有更好的机会…
when he had the opportunity, as a reporter,
去某个令人兴奋，景致怡人的地方
to be in some very exciting and dramatic places.
不是所有人都会埋在克里姆林宫
It isn't everybody can be buried in the Kremlin,
他是唯一一个埋在那里的美国人
and he's the only American.
出生在俄勒冈州的波特兰
Born in Portland, Oregon.
这是不是很特别？
Now, isn't that something?
[1915年，波特兰] -他在拥抱什么？ -一个雕像
- What's he hugging? - A statue.
我看得出来，但它是个什么雕像？
Well, I can see that. But what's it a statue of?
只是雕像，伍沃先生
It's just a statue, Mr. Woodward.
-多少钱？ -75美元
- How much is it? - It's $75.
-相片的价钱？ -没错，卢太太
- For a photograph? - That's right, Mrs. Rudisile.
这真有趣，楚太太
This is interesting, Mrs. Trullinger.
这不仅不怎么好，而且也算不上油画
Not that it isn't very nice, but it isn't a painting.
伍沃先生，请你看看这个
Mr. Woodward, I'd like you to look at this.
-我能看出作者的意图 -是的
- I think I see the intention here. - Yes.
黄昏俯瞰图
Eve dominates, you see?
梦想俯瞰梦想家
The dream dominates the dreamer.
这个…
It's...
我感觉比较模糊
It looks blurry to me.
另一个看起来也有点模糊
The other one looked blurry, too.
这是摄影师的意图，伍沃先生
I think that's the intention of the photographer, Mr. Woodward.
什么？故意整模糊？
What? To be blurry?
如果你用另一种观点去看…
But perhaps if you looked at it from a different point of view...
路易丝
Louise!
这是你吗？
This is you?
体形真好
Lovely figure.
路易丝，你是不是疯了？
Louise, have you taken leave of your senses?
别傻了，保罗
Don't be a fool, Paul.
反对自己妻子在半数熟人面前裸体…
You think I'm a fool because I object to my wife
你竟认为我傻？
being displayed naked in front of half the people I know...
是的，它不过是画廊的一幅艺术品
Yes. My God, it's a work of art in a gallery.
你是怎么啦？
What's the matter with you?
你常把波特兰看成是个 死气沉沉的地方
You used to call Portland a stuffy provincial coffin for the mind.
它可能乏味，可能偏狭
It may be stuffy and provincial,
但也是我赖以生计的地方
but it also happens to be a coffin where I earn a living.
既然你可以在此谋生…
You can take your living and fill up teeth with it,
我也可以
because I can earn my own living.
我有自己的工作
I have my work.
你把发表《政府公报》上的 几篇文章当作你的工作？
You consider a few articles in The Oregonian and The Gazette work?
不，我告诉你什么才是工作，路易丝
No, I'll tell you what your work is, Louise.
成为公众的焦点才是你的工作
It's making yourself the center of attention.
它会让路易丝・楚林杰成为 波特兰的自由女性
It's shocking Louise Trullinger, emancipated woman of Portland.
现在我们去向这些人道晚安 然后回家
Now, we're gonna say good night to these people and go home.
-我要去自由主义俱乐部 -你不能去
- I'm going to the Liberal Club. - You're not going to the Liberal Club.
-我要去，保罗 -不能去…
- I'm going to the Liberal Club, Paul. - No, you're not...
全都很漂亮，楚太太
It's very nice, Mrs. Trullinger. All of it.
这些话让你心满意足了吧，路易丝？
It's very gratifying to hear, isn't it, Louise?
是不是，路易丝？
Isn't it, Louise?
不用说也知道 谁要去自由主义俱乐部
Of course, you know who is going to be at the Liberal Club.
美国爱国者信仰自由
Patriotic Americans believe in freedom.
若我们不愿拿起武器维护这个传统…
And unless we are willing to take arms to defend our heritage,
我们就无法自称为美国爱国者
we cannot call ourselves patriotic Americans!
我为自由自豪
I'm proud to be free.
我为自己是美国人自豪
I'm proud to be an American.
若我们选举出来的总统…
And if the man we elected President decides
时刻为我们的自由而担忧…
that our freedoms are being threatened
那世界将因民主而变得安全祥和…
and that the world must be made safe for democracy,
由此也让我知道 在爱国的行列中我并不孤单！
then I know I won't be alone in heeding the call of patriotism!
这是场什么战争？
What is this war about?
每个人都会有自己的答案
Each man will have his own answer.
我也有，我等待着祖国的召唤！
I have mine. I'm ready to be called!
今晚，我们请到了…
Now, tonight we have with us
玛格丽特和已故的波特兰 C.J.雷德先生之子
the son of Margaret and the late C.J. Reed of Portland,
他亲眼目睹了这场战争
who has witnessed this war first-hand.
我认为自由主义俱乐部的全体成员…
And I, for one, see no reason why we here at the Liberal Club
都应该听听杰克・雷德的现身说法
shouldn't listen to what Jack Reed has to say.
你认为这场战争 是关于什么的，杰克・雷德？
What would you say this war is about, Jack Reed?
利润
Profits.
他说什么？
What did he say?
雷德先生 你好，我是路易丝拜伦
Excuse me, Mr. Reed. Hello, my name is Louise Bryant
我是个记者
and I am a journalist.
可否花点时间接受我的采访
And I was wondering if you might have time to give me an interview.
抱歉，不行，我不接受采访的
I'm sorry, I don't. I don't do interviews.
前不久我曾在《冲击波》上发表过文章
I had a piece in the Blast not long ago.
-伯克曼的《冲击波》？ -是的
- Berkman's Blast? Really? - That's right.
你什么时候想采访？
Well, when did you want to do this interview?
现在
Now.
我并不住这里
I don't live here.
-住在河边的一所屋子里 -是嘛？
- I live in a house by the river. - Oh, really.
天哪，狡兔三窟啊
My, my, my. Two places.
是的，这里是工作室
Yeah, I use this place as a studio.
喜欢白色百合吗？
Do you like white lilies?
那是我最喜欢的花
They're my favorite flowers.
-你还没结婚吧？ -没有，我不相信婚姻
- You're not married, are you? - No, I don't think I believe in marriage.
-你结婚了吗？ -婚姻？
- Are you married? - Marriage?
怎么会有人相信婚姻？
How could anyone believe in marriage?
想必你母亲看到你回波特兰一定很开心
I bet your mother's glad to see you back in Portland.
只有我不坐牢时她才开心 这是你吗？
Just glad when I'm not in jail. Is this you?
是的，喜欢吗？
Yes. Do you like it?
喜欢，我觉得它们…
Yeah. I think they're...
-有点模糊，不过这张很好 -是的
- A little blurry, but this one's very nice. - Yes.
是的，现在…
It is. Now...
世界经济的牟利动机…
Granted, the profit motive in the world economy
是导致战争的根源
is a basic root cause for the war.
你认为那些赞成战争 把动机归咎于爱国心的美国人…
Do you feel that those Americans who are pro-war
是不是出于愤世嫉俗或者天真？
and who ascribe their motives to patriotism are cynical or naive?
如果他们愤世嫉俗 那些玩世不恭的爱国者…
And, if they're cynical, is it the cynicism of patriots
认为如果没有牟利动机…
who feel that without a profit motive,
这个国家的领导层就不会涉足战争
the power structure elite of this country will not enter the war,
即便他们认为…
even though they feel that the containment
德国军国主义的牵制政策也许有必要…
of German militarism may be necessary for...
好吧，拜伦小姐 你想采访吗？写下来
All right, Miss Bryant, do you want an interview? Write this down.
你有没天真地想过…
Are you naive enough to think
德国的军国主义和这场战争有关？
containing German militarism has anything to do with this war?
你难道不明白英法两国占有世界经济…
Don't you understand that England and France own the world economy
而德国人想从中分一杯羹？
and Germany just wants a piece of it?
继续写，拜伦小姐
Keep writing, Miss Bryant.
拜伦小姐，你难道不明白JP摩根…
Miss Bryant, can't you grasp that J.P. Morgan
向英法贷款10亿美元的含义？
has loaned England and France a billion dollars?
如果德国人获胜，他就收不回钱
And if Germany wins, he won't get it back.
还有咖啡吗？到时美国就会介入…
More coffee? America would be entering the war
以维护摩根的金钱
to protect J.P. Morgan's money.
如果他失败了，我们就会消沉
If he loses it, we'll have a depression.
因此，真正的问题是…
So, the real question is,
我们为何有这样一种经济 穷人出钱…
why do we have an economy where the poor have to pay
以确保富人不会失去钱？
so the rich won't lose money?
我们还有什么没谈及？
All right, now, what haven't we covered?
对女性的经济自由意味着性自由
Economic freedom for women means sexual freedom,
性自由意味着节育…
and sexual freedom means birth control...
反对！《大众》持反对意见
Dissent! The Masses stands for dissent.
我们有中上阶级的…
...we have a predominantly
读者群优势
upper-middle class readership.
我们必须在全国奔走呼告 为本杂志集资
So, we have to run around the country raising money for the magazine
不择手段地…
any way we...
怎么啦？
What?
我在想…
Well, I'm thinking that I guess I...
我应该给你提供多点咖啡
That I ought to offer you more coffee.
我没留意到时间，但是…
I hadn't realized the hour, but
我似乎占用了你很多时间
I seem to have taken up a lot of your time.
没关系
Well, that's okay by me.
这种事常发生吗？
Does this happen to you often?
不经常
Not often enough.
那么…
Well?
我们进展迅速
We certainly have come a long way fast.
是的
Yeah.
你想更进一步吗？
Do you want to take it a step further?
好的
Yeah.
如果我要你做件听似有点自私的事…
What would you think if I asked you to do something
你会怎么想？
that might seem a little selfish?
我觉得你大可说出来
Well, I... I think you should.
好的，我想让你看看我的作品
Good. Good, because I'd like you to take a look at my work
发表一下你的看法
and tell me what you think.
我真的很尊重你的观点
You see, I really respect your opinion so much.
真是凑巧，我正想问你…
Well, it's odd, because I was just gonna ask you
有什么东西给我看的
if you had anything I could take a look at.
这有点强人所难 但我真的感激你能过目
I know it's an imposition but I'd be very grateful and you see,
你所写的文章我都看过
I've read everything that you've ever written.
我很乐意这么做…
Well, I'd be happy to do it. So, that's...
谢谢你
Well, thank you.
那我去给你拿外套
Well, then I... I'll get your coat.
希望你不会太客气
Oh, and I hope you won't be gentle with me.
-客气？ -我是个严肃的作家
- Gentle? - I'm a serious writer.
你大可以尖锐点
You can really be tough.
我会的…
No, I will be. No, I will be.
-谢谢 -谢谢
- Thank you. - Thank you.
-你想要我离开？ -不是的，只是我要迟到了
- Do you want me to leave? - Not really, but I'm late.
-清早6点迟到？ -是的，我有个约会
- Late at 6:00 in the morning? - Yes. I have an appointment.
明晚我可以见你吗？
Well, could I see you tomorrow night?
我明晚很忙
I'm busy tomorrow night.
-第二天我就要出城了 -真是遗憾
- Because I'm leaving town the next day. - Gee, I'm sorry.
你若有时间的话，请告知我你的看法
So, if you have time, let me know what you think,
我会把采访的副本给你
and I'll send you a copy of the interview.
采访？
Some interview, huh?
有时间看看
Take a look sometime.
好的，我明白
Yeah. Yeah, yeah. Okay, I understand.
-拜 -拜
- Bye. - Bye.
杰克，你还记得哈迪森先生吗？
Jack, dear, do you remember Mr. Hardison?
曾在山上的第一长老教堂待过
Used to be at the First Presbyterian Church, up the hill.
他现在在西雅图的普利茅斯大教堂
He's in Seattle now at the big Plymouth church.
是什么风把你吹来的，杰克？
What brings you out here, Jack?
只是回来看你母亲吗？
Just come out to see your mother?
帕洛先生，我是为我撰写的 杂志集资而来
Mr. Partlow, I just... I'm raising money for this magazine that I write for.
-什么？ -我是来为我写的杂志…
- What? - I say, I'm raising money
集资而来
for this magazine that I write for!
-杂志？什么杂志？ -是的，先生
- Magazine? What magazine? - Yes, sir.
《大众》杂志
Well, it's called The Masses.
-什么？ -《大众》
- The what? - The Masses!
-《大众》 -大众
- The Masses. - Masses.
杰克，你还记得珀森先生的妹妹吗？
Jack, do you remember Mr. Potterson's sister?
一条胳膊残废了的那个？
The one with the bad arm?
-是宗教方面的吗？ -不是的，先生
- Is that religious? - Oh, no, sir. No, sir.
你记得她的，杰克 她叫梅莉安
Oh, you remember her, Jack. Her name was Miriam.
她从不吃肉
She didn't eat meat.
有点宗教味道
Sounds religious.
记得那个向她求爱的家伙吗？
You remember the fellow that was courting her?
卖线轴的，常围着尤金转悠
Sold spool thread. Came from down around Eugene.
-不是宗教的？ -不是，先生
- Not religious, huh? - No, sir.
-他叫什么名字，杰克？ -我不记得名字了
- What was his name, Jack? - I don't think I remember the name.
我不了解你们这些人 但我真的饿了
Well, I don't know about you people, but I'm starved.
帕洛太太，我…
I don't know, Mrs. Partlow. I...
杰克，听说昨晚在自由主义俱乐部…
Jack, I heard you made a few people a little unhappy
你让一些人感到不悦了
down at the Liberal Club last night.
卡尔，我们是来这里开心的
Oh, Carl, we're here to have a good time,
不要谈那个话题
let's not go into that.
他叫什么名字，杰克？
What was his name, Jack?
-你们来了 -我不记得…
- Here you are! - I can't...
欢迎，真开心
Welcome. So happy...
-你好，杰克 -你好
- Hello, Jack. - Hello.
你气色真好
Oh, you look wonderful.
阿尔玛，这是路易丝・楚林杰
Alma, this is Louise Trullinger.
阿尔玛・波尔 这位尼德・波尔和杰克・雷德
Alma Boyle. This is Ned Boyle and Jack Reed.
杰克，路易丝是个女权改革派
Jack, Louise is quite a progressive in her own right.
帕洛先生
Mr. Partlow.
-你好，雷德先生 -你好
- How do you do, Mr. Reed? - How do you do?
帕洛先生，帕洛太太 这是路易丝・楚林杰
Oh, Mr. Partlow, Mrs. Partlow, this is Louise Trullinger.
-幸会 -幸会
- Pleased to meet you. - Pleased to meet you.
你是保罗・楚林杰的妻子？
Are you Paul Trullinger's wife?
是的
Yes. Yes, I am.
够了不起的
Well, isn't that something?
弗罗兹大桥就是他设计的
He did Frank Rhodes' bridge.
楚太太，你丈夫是全波特兰最好的牙医
Oh, Mrs. Trullinger, your husband's the finest dentist in all of Portland.
-过奖了 -是嘛？
- Thank you very much. - Really?
他还给葛洛夫叔叔做了个盘子
And I think he did a plate for Uncle Grover.
不等哈瑞和玛莎了，我快饿扁了
Oh, we won't wait for Harry and Martha. I could eat a horse.
好，我们就座吧
All right, let's go in.
保罗没来真是可惜
What a shame Paul couldn't come tonight.
-有急事？ -是的…
- An emergency? - Yes...
希望不是因为要做盘子
Not Uncle Grover's plate, I hope.
不是，那个盘子还很新
- No. Uncle Grover's plate's like new. - Oh, well...
格林威治村开始自由恋爱了？
Did free love start in Greenwich Village?
上等的红酒，卡尔
Very good wine, Carl.
-还要吗，杰克？ -不了，谢谢
- More, Jack? - No, no. No, thank you.
真的很美味
It's just delicious, really.
你不觉得吗，楚太太？
Don't you think so, Mrs. Trullinger?
是的，很美味
Yes, it's just delicious.
谢谢你，路易丝
Thank you, Louise.
-杜邦，我想是 -杜邦
- Dupont, I think. - Dupont.
是杜邦对吗，哈瑞？
It is Dupont, isn't it, Harry?
母亲不想你让杰克开谈婚姻的话题
Mother doesn't want you to get Jack started on the subject of marriage.
你有孩子吗，楚太太？
You got any children, Mrs. Trullinger?
暂时没，雷德先生
Not yet, Mr. Reed.
-叫我杰克 -我已经结婚14年了
- Call me Jack. - I've been married 14 years now.
别把我牵扯进自由恋爱的争论
Don't get me in any arguments about free love.
外面正在变冷
It's getting cold outside.
我叫你路易丝
I'll just call you Louise.
乔治・沃杜，没错 是乔治・沃杜！
George Waldorf. That's it! George Waldorf!
过去是卖线轴的
Used to sell spool thread.
-乔治・沃杜的情况呢？ -他死了
- What about George Waldorf? - Well, he died.
我无法相信 竟然没人陪你出来散步，路易丝
I couldn't think of letting you walk unescorted, Louise.
跟我说说…
Tell me something.
楚先生介意你花这么多时间 在工作室吗？
Does Dr. Trullinger mind your spending so much time at your studio?
大家都要给对方一点自由空间
People have to give each other a little freedom.
自由吗，楚太太？
Freedom, Mrs. Trullinger?
我很想知道你对自由的看法
I'd like to know what your idea of freedom is.
拥有自己的工作室？散步在…
Having your own studio? Walk...
我很想看看你脱掉裤子的样子 雷德先生
I'd like to see you with your pants off, Mr. Reed.
勇往直前
Marching and shuffling along
我没注意到时间
I didn't realize the time.
如果你不介意，那里有李子蜜饯
So, if you like, there's some very nice damson preserves.
可以用来做烤面包
And you can make toast out of that, if you want.
那么，再见
So, bye.
你去哪？
Where you going?
如果你要赶2:45的车 那就得赶紧的了
If you're catching the 2:45, I mean, you don't really have that much time.
-你要收拾的话… -路易丝，现在才8:45
- I'm sure you're gonna want to pack... - Louise, it's 8:45, only.
才8:45
It's 8:45.
我知道你在纽约非常忙
Listen, I realize that you're very busy in New York,
但如果你花点时间写点 对我作品的评价
but I'd be grateful if you could take the time
我会感激不尽
to write a few words to me about my work.
好的…
Oh, yes. Oh, yes.
如果要把我的文件包送回来 可以邮寄这个地址
If you'll just send my portfolio back. You can mail it to this address...
等等，路易丝 为什么要走得这么急？
Louise, wait a minute. What are you just walking out like that for?
请上楼来和我谈谈好吗？
Will you come upstairs, please, and just talk to me for a minute?
谢谢
Thank you.
-听着… -什么事？
- Listen... - What is it?
你不来吗？
Why don't you come?
-什么？ -来纽约
- What? - Come to New York.
你不是想写作吗？ 那就来作家云集的地方
You wanna write? Come where the writers are.
如果你有自由 那就去拥有自由的地方
If you wanna have freedom you gotta go where the freedom is, don't you?
你去波特兰是种浪费，来纽约吧
You're gonna go to waste in Portland. Come to New York.
-你应该待在纽约 -多谢了
- You ought to be in New York. - Thank you very much.
我会记得的
I'll remember that.
-什么？ -我会记得你的建议
- What? - I'll remember your advice.
请和我一起去
Please come with me.
好吧，等等 我就直接说吧
All right, wait a minute. Let me get this straight.
你想我和你一起去纽约
You want me to come with you to New York.
是的
Yeah.
以什么身份？
What as? What as?
-什么意思… -以什么身份？
- What do you mean, what... - What as?
-你的女友？ -什么意思？
- Your girlfriend? - What does that mean?
以什么身份？你的女友…
What as? Your girlfriend,
情人，情妇，还是姘妇？
your mistress, your paramour, your concubine?
为什么一定要以某种身份？
Why does it have to be as anything?
因为我不想卷进那种…
Because I don't wanna get into some kind
情感的漩涡中，我无法…
of emotional possessive involvement where I'm not able to...
我想知道是什么身份
I want to know what as.
感恩节快到了 就以火鸡的身份如何？
Well, it's nearly Thanksgiving. Why don't you come as a turkey?
我一直以为她是那种 非常认真的女孩
I always thought she was a very earnest girl who went away.
可能那个牙医除了牙齿外 对别的都一无所知
Probably the dentist knew nothing except about teeth,
有趣的是…
and was mainly interested...
那个时候她遇到这个能干的…
And then she had this wonderful journalist
可以与她海阔天空的记者
who could talk about all sorts of things.
我从德国带了件大衣
I had a coat I brought from Germany.
她想要那件大衣
And she wanted that coat
并游说了我良久
and made me all kinds of propositions.
但我也想要它
But I wanted it, too.
不过最后我还是让给了她
But finally I gave in and gave it to her.
我还有其他大衣
I had other coats.
这就是她的处世方式
So that's how she operated.
她跟随他去了，她得到了他
She went after him. As I say, she got him.
她一点都不笨
So she wasn't any dummy.
但这件事在过去的波特兰 引起了不小轰动
But it was something to happen in little old Portland.
那时你听不到性这个词
You didn't hear the word "sex."
听不到女同性恋这个词
You didn't hear the word "lesbian."
听不到男同性恋这个词
You didn't hear the word "homosexual."
也听不到流产这个词
You didn't hear the word "abortion."
那些东西你都听不到
You didn't hear those things.
男人尊重女人
Men respected women.
男人帮助女人穿外套，为女人开门
They helped them on with their coats, they opened the doors for them.
男人和女人相互求爱
And the man and woman who courted each other,
两厢情愿
they married each other.
我最大的感触就是…
You know something that I think,
那时和现在简直可以说是判若两样
that there was just as much fucking going on then as now.
只有现在，才会产生不正当的品质
Only now, it has a more perverted quality.
现在不会再有什么爱了
Now there's no love whatever included.
在那时，人间处处都有温情在
Then, there was your heart, a bit of heart in it.
那就是格林威治村
Greenwich Village was there,
被纽约城包围着
and New York was around it.
纽约其他地方和格林威治村完全不同
And the rest of New York did not act the way Greenwich Village did, exactly.
村子是异议的中心…
It was sort of a center of dissent
在美国人的生活中生活了很久
and had been for a long time in American life.
全国各地的人来到这里
People from all over the country came there.
他们被当作是吉普赛人 他们的生活方式没有规律
They were regarded as bohemian. Their ways of life were irregular.
他们的穿着…
The way they dressed
还有他们的思维方式
and certainly the way they thought
与美国的主流生活格格不入
was outside the mainstream of American life.
根据我的回忆…
And as I recollect it,
婚姻在格林威治村并不重要
marriage was not important in Greenwich Village.
我记得杰克对别人说过一句话
I remember hearing a line Jack said to somebody
他想引诱女人上床
he was trying to lure into bed.
女人非常卖弄风情 然后他说“你难道不够异教吗？”
She was being very coy, and he said, "Aren't you pagan enough?"
哈罗？
Hello?
哈罗，杰克？
Hello, Jack?
《大众》
“大工会联盟”
“周五乘列车在6号站台到达”
“我自己能找到路，路易丝”
如果散发节育小册子是违法的…
If it's illegal to hand out pamphlets on birth control,
那我也为罪犯而骄傲
I'm proud to be a criminal.
没人跟你争执坐牢权利的问题，埃玛
No one is arguing with your inalienable right to go to jail, Emma.
我只是说因为节育而坐牢…
All I'm saying is that this is not the right time
在时间上不合时宜
to go to jail for birth control.
因节育而坐牢有合适的时间吗？
Oh, there's a right time to go to jail for birth control?
《大众》现在管制起道德良心来了？
The Masses is governing conscience now?
很快你就无法区别出《纽约时报》了
Soon you'll be indistinguishable from The New York Times.
埃玛，我只是说反战运动…
Emma, all I'm saying is that you are too valuable
-对你来说代价太高 -你错了
- to the anti-war movement. - You're wrong.
-不，他说得没错，如果卷入战争… -你也错了
- No, he's right. If we get into this war... - And you're wrong.
-你让我说完好吗？ -没必要说完
- Will you let me finish my sentence? - Your sentence is not worth finishing.
成千上万的美国妇女过度操劳，营养不良
Thousands of American women, overworked, underfed,
产下的贫血孩子连一年都活不了
are dying, giving birth to anemic children who can't last out a year.
她们的生命难道就没美国男人重要？
Are their lives any less valuable than thousands of American boys'?
-星期二我要收回 -我不是说，你认为…？
- I want those back Tuesday. - I'm not saying... Do you think?
-该死 -完全正确
- Oh, shit. - Exactly.
晚安
Good night.
-要咖啡吗？ -“蔡斯桑博牌”的？
- You want some coffee? - Chase and Sanborn?
-我没咖啡了 -又没了？我走了
- I'm out of coffee. - Again? I'm leaving.
不，谈话结束了 你是个记者，杰克
No, the conversation is over. You're a journalist, Jack.
等你成为革命者时 我们再考虑优先问题
When you're a revolutionary, we'll discuss priorities.
希望咖啡真的没了
Hopefully over coffee.
-很晚了，我送你回家吧 -为什么？我不会伤害任何人
- It's late, I'll walk you home. - Why? I won't hurt anybody.
对了…
Well...
没错
Yeah.
今晚是周五晚
It's Friday night.
很高兴见到你
I'm so glad to see you.
真的，见到你很高兴
Really, I'm so glad to see you.
我看完你的文章了，写得非常好
I finished your articles. They're very good.
铁路文章，我认为还需要推敲润色
The railroad piece, I think, is... Needs polishing.
-内容有重复，但是… -但是经过深思熟虑
- It's repetitious, but... - But that's deliberate.
我是通过重复发表观点
I'm using repetition to make a point.
我不希望它润色过度
I don't want it to seem too polished.
Oh.
我认为你会喜欢纽约的
Well, I think you're gonna love New York.
埃玛…
Emma, Emma, Emma.
全名应该是埃玛・高柏
I think it was Emma Goldberg.
我觉得是
I think so.
我从未忘记埃玛・高曼
I never forgot Emma Goldman.
她启发我达到很深的思想深度
She inspired me to the very depths.
麦斯・伊斯曼是大家都喜欢的人
And Max Eastman was a beloved man.
思想激进，崇尚自由灵魂
The real radical, a free spirit.
他和埃玛・高曼是一个组的
He was in that same group with that Emma Goldman.
她应该姓高曼，不是高柏
That was her name. Goldman, not Goldberg.
弗洛伊德・戴尔是其中一员
Floyd Dell was one of them.
他写过小说，很优秀的小说
He wrote novels, beautiful novels.
激进分子包括世界产业工人组织
The radicals included people like the IWWs
还有比尔・海沃
and Bill Haywood.
还有沃特・李普曼
And there were Walter Lippmann,
林肯・史蒂芬和伊莎多拉・邓肯
and Lincoln Steffens and Isadora Duncan
以及埃娜・圣文森特・米莱
and Edna St. Vincent Millay.
埃弗德・史蒂里茨
Alfred Stieglitz...
玛格丽特・桑格
Oh, and Margaret Sanger.
天哪，我保护过她
My Lord, I picketed for her.
当然，伟大的作家尤金・奥尼尔…
And, of course, the great writer Eugene O'Neill
也是出自那里的
came from down there.
至今我仍认为 没有人可以企及奥尼尔
I don't think there's anybody who can touch O'Neill today.
我认为，要成为艺术家 必须具有一点叛逆精神
You have to be a bit of a rebel to be an artist of any kind, I believe.
格林威治村民都有点叛逆
And everybody in Greenwich Village was a bit of a rebel.
-你是做什么的，路易丝？ -写文章
- What do you do, Louise? - I write.
很好嘛，可以把面包递给我吗？
Good for you. Could you pass the bread, please?
-谢谢 -对中产阶级的美国人而言…
- Thanks. - Because to the middle-class American,
左派的人都是一样的 无政府主义者，社会主义者…
everyone on the left is the same. An anarchist, a socialist...
把面包递给我好吗？
Would you pass the bread, please?
-你是做什么的，路易丝？ -写文章
- What do you do, Louise? - I write.
不错，舒曼・汉克夫人…
Good. Madame Schumann-Heink...
杰克说你是写文章的，拜伦小姐 你写的是哪类文章？
Jack tells me you write, Miss Bryant. What do you write about?
什么都写
Everything.
什么都写？
You write about everything?
是的，什么都写，无所不写
Everything. Yes. Everything, nothing...
只是…
Just...
我明白了
I see.
戴维斯和斯隆，他们辞职了？
Now, about Davis and Sloan, have they quit?
还没，不过他们…
Not yet, but they...
我认为他们不该这样坐在这里 这样太残酷
I don't think they should sit here like this. I don't. I think it's cruel.
-只是… -组织，对吧？
- It's just... - Organization, right?
资本家是做什么的？
Look, what does a capitalist do?
请允许我问你这个问题，麦克？ 告诉我
Let me ask you that, Mike. Huh? Tell me.
他们除了赚钱之外还干什么？
I mean, what does he make, besides money?
我不知道 所有工作都是工人做的，不是吗？
I don't know what he makes. The workers do all the work, don't they?
如果工人都被组织起来呢？
Well, what if they got organized?
我是说所有的工人 不仅仅是水管工人…
I mean, all the workers. Not just the plumbers,
还有木匠，雪茄师傅
and the carpenters and the goddamn cigar makers.
世界上所有的工人
But all of them, all over the world?
不仅仅是一个国家的 给他瓶啤酒好吗？
Not in just one country. Give him a beer, will you?
如果他们都被组织起来呢？
What if they all got organized?
难道你不认为他们可以… 可以改变社会秩序
Don't you think they could... They could change society overnight.
他们可以把社会 变成他们喜欢的模式
They can make it into anything they wanted.
杰克，可否给我5块钱？我没钱了
Jack, can I tap you for $5? I'm flat.
别跟这个自命不凡的家伙要钱
Well, don't ask this pretentious son of a bitch for money.
如果你需要5块钱，我可以给你
If you need $5, I'll give it to you.
给我4块5好吗？
Let me have $4.50, will you?
-公平是什么？ -明白我的意思吗？
- What isn't fair? - You see what I'm saying?
如果全世界所有工人 都属于一个大公会
If all the workers in the world belonged to one big union,
-那就不会有战争了，是吗？ -你在听我说吗？
- there wouldn't be a war, would there? - Are you listening to me?
拜伦小姐
Miss Bryant.
你守着那瓶啤酒已经一个小时了
You've been nursing that beer for an hour.
要不要给你来杯红酒？
Can I get you a glass of wine or something?
不用了，谢谢，我没事
No, thank you. I'm fine. Thank you, anyway.
-啤酒就好 -你是个亲切的人
- Beer's fine. - You are an amiable person.
听说也是个好画家
And a very good painter, I hear.
我是作家
I write.
看过杨
Read Jung!
看过弗洛伊德，看过杨 看过恩格斯，麦斯
"Read Freud, read Jung." Read Engels, read Marx!
天哪，你不能把弗洛伊德 加入到经济范筹
My God, you can't interpret Freud in an economic context.
你知道出租车在等你吗？
You know you got a taxi waiting?
索斯玛代表了宗教堕落
Zosima represents the corruption of religion.
你这观点是错的
I tell you you're wrong.
-杨是个神秘的… -但你真的认为…
- And Jung is a mystic... - But do you seriously believe...
-他们要赖多久才走？ -不知道，应该快走了
- How long are they going to stay? - I don't know. They'll get out in a while.
-我只离开一天而已 -你可刚从波士顿回来
- I'll only be gone for a day. - You just got back from Boston.
你何不和我一起去巴尔的摩？
Hey, why don't you come with me to Baltimore?
真的？我应该以什么身份去？
Really? What am I supposed to come to Baltimore as?
什么身份？
What as?
杰克，出租车在等你呢
Jack, you know, you got a taxi waiting.
出租车在等呢，杰克
Taxi's waiting, Jack.
明天见
See you tomorrow.
我们努力了两年
We've been trying for two years.
资本家们可随时根据 自己的意愿让国家卷入战火
Capitalists can take this country into war any time they damn well please.
你唯一能施加影响的地方就是街道
The only impact you can make is in the streets.
当然，可是…
Of course, but...
可是，埃玛，你难道不认为…
But don't you think, Emma,
如果戴布斯获得很多选票 这会否强化这种印象？
that if Debs gets a lot of votes, it'll strengthen that image?
不，不会的，我认为选举 是这个国家的鸦片
No, I don't. I think voting is the opium of the masses in this country.
每4年就要遭受这样的痛苦
Every four years, you deaden the pain.
是的，但是…
Yeah, but...
你不认为…
Don't you think...
我已经很清楚地 表达了自己的想法，拜伦小姐
I just made it very clear what I think, Miss Bryant.
别这样，埃玛，不要这么独断
Come on, E.G. Don't be so goddamn dogmatic.
-路易丝有她自己的看法 -我突然变得独断了？
- Louise has a point. She says... - Suddenly I'm dogmatic.
为何我每次身份改变 你就会带一个新的女人来，杰克？
Why does my status change every time you get a new woman, Jack?
伯尼，可以给我来点红酒吗？ 路易丝，你要吗？
Bernie, could I have the red wine? Louise, would you like a glass?
她有点…她有点烦我
She's just... She's upset with me.
这跟你没关系，和你无关
It's got nothing to do with you. Nothing to do with you.
谢谢，这话很舒心
Thank you. It's a great comfort.
你离开后屋子里都挤满了人
The house is completely filled with people when you're gone.
他们简直把它当会议室了
They use it as if it was a meeting hall or something.
-我根本没法工作 -那就赶他们走
- I can't get any work done. - Just throw them out.
-怎么赶？ -直接赶走
- How am I supposed to throw them out? - Just kick them out.
叫他们离开
Tell them to leave.
我不会叫麦斯・伊斯曼离开
I'm not going to say to Max Eastman, "Leave."
-只管赶他们走 -杰克？
- Just throw them out. - Jack?
杰克，是你吗？ 见到你太高兴了
Jack, is that you? Jack, it's very good to see you.
-贺瑞斯，近来好吗？ -很高兴见到你
- Hello, Horace. How are you? - Very good to see you.
-认识路易丝・拜伦吧？ -你好
- You know Louise Bryant? - Yes, hello. How are you?
-很高兴见到你 -你好
- Very nice to see you. - How do you do?
幸会
Great pleasure.
-嗨，麦斯，你好吗？ -你好，贺瑞斯
- Hi, Max. How are you? - Divine, Horace.
-幸会，弗洛伊德 -你好，贺瑞斯
- And Floyd, good to see you. - Hello, Horace.
牢狱之灾还是不断吗，杰克？
Still getting arrested, Jack?
试试吧
I try.
你呢，拜伦小姐？
How about you, Miss Bryant?
你也想尝试被捕吗？
Are you trying to get arrested, too?
不，不想
No, not really.
-你是做什么的，拜伦小姐？ -写文章
- What do you do, Miss Bryant? - I write.
写文章？可否说一下都写些什么吗？
You write? Now, may I ask, what are you working on?
无法形容
It's impossible to describe.
无法形容？
It's impossible to describe?
她刚刚写了篇文章
She just did a hell of a piece
在纽约军械库展上反响很大 你应该读读
on the influence of the Armory Show and you ought to read it.
那我真的要读一读了
Well, you know, I very much would like to read that.
何不打电话到《大都会》找我？
Why don't you give me a call at The Metropolitan?
或是周二我们出来喝两杯如何？
In fact, even better, why don't we have a drink on Thursday?
-好吧 -我们可以聊聊纽约军械库展
- Fine. - We can talk about the Armory Show.
-就这么约定了 -好吧
- It's a date, then. - Well, all right.
太好了
That's wonderful. Fine.
杰克！
Jack!
别再被逮进去了，好吗？
Now, you stay out of the slammer, now, okay?
再见，见到你很高兴
Goodbye. Goodbye. Goodbye. It's nice to see you.
-杰克，不要这样做 -什么？
- Jack, please don't do that. - What?
他是《大都会》的编辑 我认识他好几年了
He's the editor of Metropolitan. I've known him for years.
-杰克，我可以为自己辩护 -你的文章也可以
- Jack, I can speak for myself. - So can your work.
-我不想你这样做… -出租车在等着了，杰克
- I don't want you to do that... - Taxi's waiting, Jack.
出租车在等着了，杰克
Oh. Taxi's waiting, Jack.
杰克
Jack...
周末见，好吗？
I'll see you at the end of the week, okay?
-好吗？ -等等
- Okay? - Wait. Wait.
或许我周四会给他电话
Maybe I will call him about Thursday.
好的，周四给他电话
Yeah, call him about Thursday. Yeah, yeah.
-再见，各位 -再见，杰克
- See you, boys. - Bye-bye, Jack.
-再见，杰克 -再见
- Bye-bye, Jack. - See you.
再见，杰克
See you, Jack.
“铁路延伸到新的国境”
"The railroad's opening new frontiers,
“所有的铁路交叉纵横”
"and crisscrossing it all are the railroads.
“铁路延伸到新的国境”
"The railroad's opening new frontiers,
“依次地，这些国境…”
"and in turn, these frontiers...
"And in turn, these frontiers..."
哦，天哪
Oh, God.
这是重复
It is repetitious.
我们不是人，我们是商品
We're not human beings, we're a commodity.
-一周工作多少天？ -七天
- And how many days a week? - Seven days.
-每天工作？ -他们说了…
- Every day? - They said,
如果你周日不来上班 周一就不要来了
"If you don't come to work on Sunday, don't come on Monday."
-一小时工钱是多少？ -20美分
- What do you make an hour? - 20 cents.
因为工作不熟练，他们有多少次…
How many times have they slammed the door on your face
让你们吃闭门羹？
because the labor you do is called unskilled?
没事的，比尔
That's right, Bill.
世界产业工人组织 不会因你们技术不熟练…
Well, the IWW's not gonna turn you down
-就把你们拒之门外 -听他的，乔治
- because you're unskilled. - Listen to him, George.
肤色不限，黑色，白色，黄色都行
Or skilled. Or black or white or yellow.
一周工作7天
Seven days a week.
-一小时工钱是多少？ -10美分
- What do you make an hour? - 10 cents an hour.
一个大工会联盟
One big union.
-所有工人都属于… -都看看，这很重要
- All workers belong... - Listen, read that. That's important.
我在找一个叫 帕斯奎・埃伯迪的车工
I'm looking for a lathe worker named Pasquale Alberti.
他出了工伤事故，腿被压断了 认识他吗？
He had an industrial accident. He got his leg crushed. Do you know him?
当然认识，哈佛
Yeah, sure, Harvard.
这就是他们在格林威治村所报导的？
Is that what they wanna read about in Greenwich Village now,
工伤事故？
industrial accidents?
因此，我们需要权力
And for that, we need power.
只有一种方式才能获得权力
And there's only one way to get power.
组织起来
Organize!
所有工人一条心
All the workers together!
一个大工会！
One big union!
世界产业工人组织需要你们 加入到阶级斗争中来
And the war the IWW wants you to get into is class war!
欧洲没有战争！
Not a war in Europe!
推翻资产阶级！
War against the capitalists!
你们会一无所有
You'll never get anything or anywhere,
除非整个工人阶级属于一个大…
until the whole working class belongs to one big...
好了，先生们
All right, gentlemen,
你们有20秒的时间离开
you've got 20 seconds to vacate the premises.
你们有何授权？
May I ask on what authority?
我的授权
On my authority.
这是非法集会
This is an illegal assembly.
对不起，警官 这些人都是合法集会的
Excuse me, Officer. These men have the legal right to assemble.
这就是他们正在做的事情
That's all they're doing.
我们知道他们做什么
We know what the hell they doing.
-你在这里做什么？ -我？
- What the hell you doing? - Me?
就是你
You.
-我写作 -写作？
- I write. - You write?
你错了
You wrong.
把他带走！
Get him out of here!
就是它们哪
Here they are.
对开的纸，全部作品
The folio. The oeuvre.
Well...
杰克还好吗？
How is Jack?
希望他最近写作最好能小心谨慎点
I do hope he's being more careful about what he's writing these days.
我不想看到他的作品无法出版
I'd hate to see him not able to get into print.
他能应付得来的
Oh, I'm sure he'll do fine.
你告诉他我们在哪里喝酒了吗？
Did you tell him where we were having drinks?
没有，我会的，他出城了
No, I will. He's out of town.
威汉先生，对不起 纽约军械库展的文章在最上面
Mr. Whigham, excuse me, but the Armory Show piece is on the top.
这是军械…
Oh, this is the Armory...
-是的 -是的，当然
- Yes. - Yes. Of course. Here it is.
Well...
我还需要点时间来拜读
I really ought to spend more time on this.
当然可以
Oh, yes, of course.
共进晚餐如何？
What about dinner?
-晚餐？ -杰克不会介意的
- Dinner? - Jack wouldn't mind.
-他为什么要介意？ -当然，我们都是成年人了
- Why would he mind? - Well, we're all grownups, of course,
不过杰克非常的…
but Jack's rather...
他是个非常古怪的家伙
He's rather an odd duck, isn't he?
我一直不知道…
And I've never really known how...
威汉先生，你是说…
Mr. Whigham, are you saying you need
和我约会要获得杰克的许可？
Jack's permission to make a pass at me?
不要为此烦恼
Don't get so upset about it.
老天，我作了两个小小变动
For Christ's sake, I made two little tiny changes...
不要修改我写的，彼得
Don't rewrite what I write, Pete.
你到底是怎么了，杰克？
What the hell's the matter with you, Jack?
世界产业工人组织是赤色份子
The IWW's a bunch of Reds.
拜托
Come on.
世界产业工人组织有赤色份子 村子里有赤色份子
We got Reds in the IWW, got Reds in the Village.
除了赤色份子这里什么都没有
We've got nothing but Reds around here.
老天，你是这里最好的作家
For Christ's sake, you're the best goddamn writer around.
你何必浪费时间和精力…
Now, what the hell you wanna waste your time
来写那些别人不会出版的赤色文章？
with a lot of Red propaganda nobody's ever gonna print?
这是真理，这理由够充分吗？
It's the truth. Does that mean anything around here?
谁说那些东西是真理的？
Well, who the hell's to say what the truth is?
世界产业工人组织的那帮赤色份子？
A bunch of goddamn Reds in the IWW?
你对左派那些人并不公平
You're not being fair to the AF of L.
-快把那篇文章给我 -你要修改我的文章？
- Now, give me the goddamn article... - You're gonna rewrite what I write.
我拿给愿意出版的杂志社
I'm just gonna take it to a magazine that won't.
好吧，拿去给《大众》
Well, fine. Take it to The Masses.
-他们是帮赤色份子 -谢谢
- They're a bunch of Reds. - Thank you.
-谁来支付你的租金？ -这你不用担心，彼得
- Who's gonna pay your rent? - Rent's easy, Pete.
你不要修改我的文章就行，明白吗？
You just don't rewrite what I write. You got that? Don't rewrite what I write.
你这倔驴子，谁来支付你的租金？
You stubborn son of a bitch. Who's gonna pay your rent?
路易丝？
Louise?
我把店里的都买来了
I got every one in the shop.
我们虽然窘迫，但我还是都买下了
We're broke, but we've got them all.
谢谢
Thanks.
-怎么了？ -没什么
- What's the matter? - Nothing.
-怎么了？ -没事，旅途如何？
- What is it? - It's nothing. How'd it go?
比预期的要好多了
A lot better than we thought it would.
-你见到威汉了？ -昨天见了
- You see Whigham? - Yesterday.
-怎么样？ -我们主要还是谈你的事
- How was that? - We mostly talked about you, of course.
他给你提供工作了？
Did he offer you work?
没有，不过他向我大说特说…
No, but he made a big point of telling me
你和他这么多年的友情有多伟大
what wonderful friends you and he have become over the years.
这是次美好会面
It was a fascinating meeting.
你是在生威汉的气还是生我的气？
Are you angry at Whigham or me?
怎么啦？
What is it?
没什么，你说过周二就回的
It's nothing. You said you'd be back Tuesday
今天都周六了
and it's Saturday.
我不是说周末回家吗？
Didn't I say I'd back at the end of the week?
-周末是星期五 -周末是星期五？
- The end of the week is Friday. - The end of the week is Friday?
星期六不是周末了？
Saturday's not the end of the week anymore, huh?
杰克，你说过周二就回的！
Jack, you said you'd be back Tuesday!
这有什么区别？
What difference does it make?
你认为我一直在做什么？
What do you think I've been doing?
到处跑去听自己夸夸其谈吗？
Running around listening to the sound of my own voice?
我怎么知道你去听谁夸夸其谈？
How do I know whose voice you've been listening to?
显然你喜欢它更胜过我！
Obviously you like it a lot better than mine!
天哪，看看我
Look at me. Oh, God!
我就像一个妻子
I'm like a wife.
我就像一个烦人的 粘人的，痛苦的小妻子
I'm like a boring, clinging, miserable little wife.
-谁会想回家看我？ -我！
- Who'd wanna come home to me? - Me!
我受不了了，我再也不能这样做了！
Well, I can't do this! I can't do this anymore!
你不能做什么？
You can't do what?
我就像是生活在你的边缘上
I'm just living in your margins.
我不知道自己在这干嘛 我不知道自己的目标是什么
I don't know what I'm doing here. I don't know what my purpose is.
-告诉我你想做什么 -我不想再需要你！
- Well, tell me what you want. - I want to stop needing you!
还有一件事
I want you to know something.
我问威汉是否可以派我去法国
I asked Whigham if he'd send me to France.
-这就是你想要的？ -没错
- Is that what you want? - That's what I want.
-你要做什么，路易丝？ -我不能在你身边工作
- What are you doing, Louise? - I can't work around you.
你为什么要这样做？
Will you tell me why you're doing this?
你在我身边时，我没法严肃起来
I'm not taken seriously when you're around.
我在你身边你没法严肃起来？
When I'm around you're not taken seriously?
天哪，简直糟透了
Oh, God, this is not good.
你认为我需要更加严肃？
You mean you think I'm taken more seriously?
你是想这样说吗？
Is that what you're talking about?
你难道不认为吗？杰克
Do you mean you're not? Come on, Jack.
你明白我在说什么，你对我一直不坦白
You know what I'm saying. You're not being honest with me.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're saying.
你对我一直不够坦白 请对我坦白点吧
You're not being honest with me. Please, be honest with me.
我对你非常的坦白
I am so being honest with you.
如果你让自己严肃一点 对方也会这样的
Maybe if you took yourself a little more seriously, other people would, too.
我告诉过你我对军械展文章的看法
I told you what I thought about the Armory piece.
我对此已经很坦白
I was honest about that.
我认为那篇文章很好 但我并没严肃对待它
I think it's very nice, but no, I don't take it very seriously.
-谢谢 -如果你的文章不严肃…
- Thank you. - Why do you even expect
你为什么又期望 别人会严肃对待它们？
to be taken seriously if you're not writing about serious things?
我不明白
I don't understand that.
我给自己找了间公寓，我要自己找一个
I found myself an apartment. I'm looking for one.
我甚至不知道 你所谓的严肃事情是什么
I'm not even sure I know what things you're serious about.
你先是写关于铁路的文章
One day you're writing about the railroads,
但却一直没写完
and you don't even finish the piece.
然后你又要写一篇发生在3年前的…
The next day you're doing a piece on an art exhibition
有关艺术展的文章
that happened three years ago.
为何你什么都要给我看？
Look, why do you give me anything to read, anyway?
如果我提出异议 你就说你喜欢这样写
If I criticize it at all, you tell me you like it the way it is.
当我们和其他人一起出去…
And when we're out with other people,
如果有人没直接问你问题…
if somebody doesn't ask you a direct question,
你就会说你觉得受到了忽视
you tell me you feel ignored.
但是，这样的事情每天都在发生
But with everything that's happening in the world today,
你决定坐下来写文章…
you decide to sit down and write a piece
写有关1913年纽约军械库展的影响
on the influence of the goddamned Armory Show of 1913!
人们应该严肃对待它吗？
Are people supposed to take that seriously?
我真的不在乎！
Well, I don't really care!
-你在乎！ -我真的不在乎！
- You care! - I'm not really... I don't care!
-你在乎 -我不在乎！
- You care! - I don't care!
你那些愚蠢朋友严不严肃对待我…
And I'm not interested in whether your stupid friends
-我并不感兴趣 -他们不会严肃对待
- take me seriously or not! - Well, they don't take it seriously.
这是因为他们并不严肃对待它
That's why they don't take it seriously.
我在休斯顿大街找了一间公寓 我要搬进去
I found an apartment on Houston Street, and I'm moving in.
我再告诉你，杰克・雷德
And I'll tell you something else, Jack Reed.
我认为我们是志不同不相为谋
I don't think we like the same people or the same kind of life.
-我要过自己的生活 -你只管走！
- And I wanna be on my own. - Go ahead, be on your own!
我不在乎，你去过你自己的吧
I don't give a damn! You're on your own anyway.
我知道你不在乎！
Oh! I know you don't give a damn!
你告诉我，我为什么要在乎？
Well, will you tell me why the hell I should give a damn?
你不该在乎！那就不要在乎！
You shouldn't! Don't give a damn!
-我也不在乎 -没错，我不在乎
- I don't give a damn, either! - That's right! I don't give a damn!
-我要离开这里 -好啊，我也离开
- I'm getting out of here! - Good, fine! I'm leaving, too!
亲爱的，我们可否离开纽约？
Honey, can we just get out of New York?
我们去别的地方，写我们想写的东西
Let's go somewhere and just write what we wanna write.
普罗旺斯是个小渔村
Provincetown was just a tiny little fishing village.
那里非常的保守
And it was very, very conservative.
我们每逢夏天 都乘坐蒸汽船去富尔河
We'd take the Fall River steamer up there, I remember, every summer.
为节省费用，都是睡在隔层硬铺
We used to save fares by sleeping in tiers.
我们经常受到臭虫的骚扰
And we always got bedbugs.
在那里喜欢做什么就做什么
You did whatever you pleased up there.
我们还表演一些非常有趣的话剧
And we put on some very interesting plays, experimental plays
那种正规剧院不会严处的话剧
that a commercial theater couldn't possibly do.
苏珊・格拉斯佩的《琐事》
Take Susan Glaspell's Trifles.
整个话剧…
There's a whole play
没有主角，甚至没有舞台
without the protagonist even appearing on the stage.
他们还举行了三场独幕戏
And they gave three one-act plays.
其中一个话剧是由…
One of them was a play by...
我一直认为是 约翰・雷德和路易丝・拜伦扮演的
I always thought it was by John Reed and Louise Bryant.
应该就是由她演的
But I see it's by her.
他们都在剧中
They were in it.
那出话剧很糟糕 而他们表现得更糟糕
The play was terrible, and they were worse.
当然，尤金・奥尼尔是以诗歌着称的
And of course, Gene O'Neill was known as the poet,
不过我喜欢他的话剧 胜过他的诗歌
but I liked his plays better than his poetry.
你怎样才能明白？
Will you never understand?
你是不是愚笨到不明白我的意思？
Are you so stupid that you do not know what I mean?
我把自己献给你
I am offering myself to you.
我跪在你的面前
I am kneeling before you.
我承诺过把身体献给你
I have promised you my body,
男人们都为之迷倒的身体
my body that men have found so beautiful.
我承诺过要爱你，黑人水手
I have promised to love you, a negro sailor!
告诉他们，不要站在月亮后面
Tell them not to stand behind the moon.
不要站在月亮后面
Don't stand behind the moon.
-后面？ -你能退后一点吗？
- Back? - Can you step back a little bit?
因为月亮
'Cause of the moon.
这是月亮
This is the moon here.
-这边？ -是的
- This way? - Yes.
从“我讨厌大海”那段开始
Take it from "I hate the sea."
你怎样才能明白？
Will you never understand?
你是不是愚笨到不明白我的意思？
Are you so stupid that you don't know what I mean?
我把自己献给你
I'm offering myself to you.
我跪在你的面前
I'm kneeling before you.
有多少男人曾经拜倒在我的面前
I... I, who have had so many men kneel before me,
我把我的身体献给你
I'm offering you my body,
男人们都为之迷倒的身体
my body that men have found so beautiful.
我承诺过要爱你
I have promised to love you.
黑人水手
You, a negro sailor.
你让我等待 这难道不是奇耻大辱吗？
Is that not humiliation enough that you must keep me waiting so?
回答我，请回答我！
Answer me, please! Answer me.
请把水给我好吗？
Will you give me that water?
我没有水
I have no water.
老泰迪想打这场战争，对吗？
Old Teddy wants this war, doesn't he?
不知道人们要多久才会 明白他是个疯子
I wonder how long it'll take the public to find out he's a maniac.
泰迪・罗斯福有狂犬病 全体军事训练
Teddy Roosevelt has rabies. Universal military training.
杰克，你的二次演讲完了
Jack, your second speech is out.
其中最讽刺的就是穷人们都爱戴他
And the ironic part of it is that poor people, they love him.
他们当然爱 他们会再次把他拥上圣胡安山
Sure, they do. They'll take him up San Juan Hill again.
你不能碰那个兔装，那是租来的
You can't touch the bunny suit. It's rented.
你有看过大会上那篇文章吗？
Did you read the piece on the convention?
如果左派不防卫威尔逊 休斯总统就遭殃了
If the left doesn't defend Wilson, we're gonna get President Hughes.
我们应该去圣路易斯吗？
Think we ought to go to St. Louis?
我不去圣路易斯保护威尔逊
I am not going to St. Louis to defend Wilson.
-我认为我们应该去 -为什么？这样做有什么好处吗？
- I think we should. - Why? What good would it do?
我不知道 如果你认为休斯不会在几个月内…
I don't know, if you don't think Hughes would have us
让我们卷入战火，那就没任何好处
in a war in a few months, it wouldn't do any good at all.
威尔逊把我们远远地排斥在外
Wilson's kept us out so far.
雷德认为自己是个好诗人
Reed thought that he was a good poet.
他是个糟糕的诗人
He was a terrible poet.
他认为自己可以写出优秀的小说
He thought that he could write good novels.
短篇小说
Short stories.
当然，他是个诗人
Of course, he was a poet.
但不是个伟大的诗人
And not a great poet,
有些诗还是不错的
but some of it was very fine.
但作为一个记者 杰克・雷德远远胜过他们
But, as a journalist, Jack Reed topped them all.
-把这个往上拉 -杰克
- Look. Pull this up. - Hey, Jack.
瞧见没？不错吧
See? That's good.
杰克，你的车来了
Jack, your ride's here.
-对不起，我在外面等 -好的
- Excuse me. I'll wait outside. - Okay. Okay.
-明白我的意思吗？如果… -杰克，出租车在等着呢
- Do you see what I mean? If one... - Jack, the taxi's waiting.
好吧，我该走了
Yeah, I got to run.
再见，亲爱的
Bye, honey.
杰克・雷德想挑起矛盾
Jack Reed wanted to stir up trouble,
他想给资产阶级带来麻烦
he wanted to stir up trouble for the capitalists.
他也想唤醒工人大众…
And he also wanted to arouse the working masses
联合起来争取一些实效
to the necessity of some kind of effective united action.
换句话说，我当他是个爱管闲事的人
In other words, I am accusing him of either being a busybody
或者说是一个胆小鬼
or of being a fraidy-cat,
不想面对自己的未来
not wanting to face things of his own nature.
亲爱的路易丝 圣路易斯现在很热，到处是民主党员
Dear Louise, St. Louis is very hot and very crowded with Democrats,
大家都很开心，戴着纸帽
all having a wonderful time and wearing little paper hats
和预料中威尔逊的任命一样
in anticipation of Wilson's nomination.
我希望这是因为…
I'd like to think it's because
他不想让美国卷入战争
he doesn't want the United States to go into the war,
但谁知道民主党人在想什么呢？
but who knows the mind of a Democrat?
对了，我已经决定摒弃那首百合诗
By the way, I've decided to throw out the poem on white lilies.
诗中的压韵错误了
The rhyming scheme was wrong.
等我回来再重写
Maybe when I get back I can start it again.
政治严重影响了诗歌创作
Politics sure plays hell with your poetry.
我一直都很想见到你，这是最迫切的
I keep thinking I see you. It's the damnedest thing.
我想你，亲爱的 想念一起在沙滩上漫步
I miss you, honey. I miss walking on the beach.
-你好 -威士忌在哪？
- Hello. - Where's the whiskey?
要杯子吗？
Would you like a glass?
别想了
Don't try and decide.
我给你拿
I'll get you one.
我喜欢你的戏
I like your play.
我好想演法官的角色
I only hope I can do the part justice.
我觉得你设计的台词太精彩了 我很喜欢…
I think your dialogue is beautiful. I really do, I love it...
那你为何不站在台上好好演…
Then why the hell don't you just stand still and say it
为何在舞台上梦游？
instead of wandering all over the stage?
你应该寻找你的灵魂 而不是找烟灰缸
You're supposed to be looking for your soul, not an ashtray.
你不希望我在彩排时抽烟吗？
Would you rather I didn't smoke during rehearsals?
我宁愿看到你引火烧身…
I'd rather you went up in flames than put out your cigarette
而不是独角戏演到一半时去抽烟
in the middle of a monologue about birth.
对不起，你批评得对
I'm sorry. You're absolutely right.
你这样做让我想取消整个制作
It makes me wanna cancel the whole production.
我不会再犯错误了，对不起
I won't do it again. Excuse me, I'm sorry.
杯子你留着，我拿酒瓶喝
You keep the glass. I'll take the bottle.
你要走了吗？
Are you leaving?
给我杯子
Give me your glass.
你紧张了？
Are you nervous?
-还是手颤？ -你为何不和杰克去芝加哥？
- Or is that a tremor? - Why aren't you in Chicago with Jack?
为什么要去？ 他有他的事，我有我的事
Why should I be? He has his things, I have mine.
-什么事？ -什么？
- What are they? - What?
你有什么事？
The things that you have that are yours.
到底什么事？
What are they?
我的工作
My work, for one.
他是个工作狂，是不是？
He's a real mean son of a bitch, isn't he?
你什么意思？
What do you mean?
把你留下来做自己的事
Leaving you alone with your work.
-你以为我介意吗？ -你应该介意
- You think I mind? - You should.
有一件事不能留下单独做
It's the one thing we mustn't be left alone with.
-你也许会这样认为，但我不会 -好
- You may feel that way, I don't. - Good.
别让那些乡村激进分子 影响了你的角色
Don't let those village radicals keep you from being what you should be.
什么角色？
What do you think I should be?
众人关注的焦点
The center of attention.
我想你身边一定不少女强人吧
Well, you must have been with some very competitive women.
是占有欲强的女人
Let's just say possessive.
占有欲强？那就另当别论了
Possessive? That's something else.
这是浪费光阴
It's a waste of time.
我不是
I'm not.
杰克也不是
Neither is Jack, for that matter.
我知道，你和杰克各有所爱
Oh, yes. I know. You and Jack have your own things.
他有自由做自己想做的事 我也是一样
He has the freedom to do the things that he wants to and so do I.
如果有谁害怕那种自由…
And I think anyone who's afraid of that kind of freedom
其实他害怕的是空虚
is really only afraid of his own emptiness.
原来你一直在给我下套
Are you making this up as you go along?
请你走吧
I'd like you to go.
为什么？
Why?
因为我不想屈尊就俯
Because I don't want to be patronized.
如果你不相信相互独立性 博爱和尊重…
I'm sorry if you don't believe in mutual independence
那么对不起了
and free love and respect.
别对我鼓吹乡村激进分子的 社会主义理论
Don't give me a lot of parlor socialism that you learned in the Village.
如果你是我的，我不会让别人分享你
If you were mine, I wouldn't share you with anybody or anything.
只有你和我，你会是中心所在
It'd be just you and me. You'd be at the center of it all.
撇下你让你独自工作…
You know, it would feel lot more like love
这不叫爱情
than being left alone with your work.
-希望我没有触怒你 -没有，我感谢都来不及
- I hope I haven't upset you. - Not at all. I'm grateful.
但是好像你要找的东西…
But you seem to be looking for something much more serious
比我所想的要严肃多了
than what I had in mind.
-比你想的严肃多了？ -是的
- Than what you had in mind? - Yes.
杰克和我都能够…
You see, Jack and I are both perfectly capable
坚持自己的信念
of living with our beliefs.
但我认为像你这样浪漫的人 会被他们的信仰摧毁
But I think someone as romantic as you would be destroyed by them.
我可不想看到这种事发生 杰克会很担心的
And I don't want that to happen. It would upset Jack too much.
“你不能来我的院子玩耍”
You can't come and play in my yard
“我再也不爱你了”
I don't love you anymore
“你看到我会难过的”
You'll be sorry when you see me
“关闭我的地窖门”
Sliding down my cellar door
“你不能对着我的雨水桶发牢骚”
You can't holler down my rain barrel
“你不能爬我的苹果树”
You can't climb my apple tree
“我不想在你的院子里玩耍”
I don't want to play in your yard
“因为你对我不好”
If you can't be good to me
“我不想在你的院子里玩耍”
I don't want to play in your yard
“我再也不喜欢你了”
I don't like you anymore
“你看到我会难过的”
You'll be sorry when you see me
“关闭我的地窖门”
Sliding down our cellar door
“你不能对着我的雨水桶发牢骚”
You can't holler down our rain barrel
“你不能爬我的苹果树”
You can't climb our apple tree
“我不想在你的院子里玩耍”
I don't want to play in your yard
“因为你对我不好”
If you won't be good to me
太美妙了！
Wonderful!
弗洛伊德，我期待已久了
Floyd, I've been waiting for this for weeks.
拿出点感觉来
Tap your sensuality.
-美妙的谢幕 -太棒了
- Wonderful close. - Extraordinary.
非常好，太棒了
Very good. Excellent.
-弗洛伊德，你没听过这首歌吧？ -麦斯，你呢？
- Floyd, that's new for you, isn't it? - Max, what about you?
-好了，下一个到谁？ -我刚朗诵完
- Okay. Who's next? - I just recited
我新作的三分之二
two-thirds of my new play.
你们都说它写得很离奇
You said it was a work of uncanny perception.
是吗？我们忘得真快
Oh, did I? How quickly we forget.
-嗨 -杰克，快进来
- Well! - Jack. Come in.
前锋标兵回来了
News from the front.
-你好，杰克 -你好，杰克
- Hello, Jack. - Hello, Jack.
-嗨，杰克 -旅途如何？
- Hi, Jack. - How was the trip?
欢迎回来
Welcome back.
-下一个到谁？ -没人了
- Who's next? - Nobody's next.
让尤金跳舞吧
Let's have a dance out of Gene.
杰克，回来得正好 能看到奥尼尔跳舞
Jack, you're just in time to see O'Neill dance.
给我们跳段爱尔兰舞吧，尤金
Okay. Do something Irish. Come on, Gene.
来一段，尤金
Yeah. Let's have it, Gene.
-跳啊，尤金 -再朗诵你的新作
- Yeah. Go ahead Gene. - Recite something from your new play.
哈奇说新作很棒
Hutch says it's wonderful.
说说大会的情况吧，杰克 威尔逊的演讲怎样？
Tell us about the convention, Jack. How was Wilson's speech?
别提演讲了，说说他的打扮吧
Never mind the speech. What was he wearing?
-威尔逊怎样了？ -对，他怎样？
- What about Wilson? - Yeah. What about Wilson?
我不觉得有何理由相信 他会采取什么措施
Oh, I don't think there's any reason to believe that Wilson's gonna do anything
他只会为维护统治阶级的利益而战
other than support the interest of the ruling class and take us into the war.
但只要他反战，我们就该支持他
But as long as he says he's against it, then I think we have to support him.
至少这几个月内 他不会违背竞选承诺…
Because he'll have to make good on that campaign promise
那样一来我们就有时间…
for at least a few months and that might give us time
巩固反战联盟
to strengthen the anti-war coalition.
但是街上的战前气氛越来越浓了
But there's a lot more pro-war feeling in the streets now than there was before...
还要喝酒吗，尤金？
You want another drink, Gene?
不喝了
I guess not.
-晚安 -晚安
- Good night. - Night.
晚安
Good night.
要不要来杯冰柠檬茶？
Would you like some cold tea with lemon?
不了，谢谢
No, thanks.
不喝我喝
Well, I'll have some, anyway.
-这是什么？ -一首诗
- What's this? - A poem.
可以看看吗？
May I read it?
我还没写完
I didn't finish it.
写完它
Finish it.
写完它？
Finish it?
如果我是个诗人，你会开心吗？
Would that make you happy? If I were a poet?
开心
I'm happy.
-杰克 -快去睡觉吧
- Jack. - Why don't you get some sleep?
杰克
Jack.
有些事我得告诉你
There's something that I have to tell you.
-你不用说了 -不用？
- You don't have to tell me anything. - No?
不用
No.
你想结婚吗？
You want to get married?
好了，进来，我看看…
Okay. There we go. I'll see...
-当心点 -还有两个呢
- Oh, careful there. Careful. - There's two more to come.
两个？不，应该有三个
Two? No, there should be three.
1916年，克洛顿哈森
对不起，我真不该唠叨个不停
Oh, excuse me. I'm sorry. I'm very sorry to hover like this.
我不是否定你们的工作
It's not that you're not doing a wonderful job.
只是我非常关心那只箱子
It's just that I'm very concerned about this one particular box.
-这里，不对 -我来拿
- Here. No. No. - I'll take it.
威士忌在哪？
Where's the whiskey?
-夫人，这个放哪？ -放那边吧
- Lady, where do you want this? - Oh, just put it over there.
可以了，谢谢
That'll be fine. Thank you.
对
Yeah.
-这里有喝的吗？ -喝的？
- Anything to drink in there? - Drink?
给你们，谢谢，非常感谢…
Oh, here. Thanks. Thank you very much. I...
-谢谢 -谢谢
- Thank you. Good. - Thank you.
我找找看，找到了
Oh. Well. Let's see now. Here we are.
-尤金？ -没有杯子吗？
- Gene? - No glass?
我找找看
Oh. Let's see.
我真应该给东西贴上标签
Well, I guess I should have labeled these, shouldn't I have?
不，不是这个
No. No, that isn't the right one.
试试这个
Try this one.
你现在在忙什么，尤金？
Well, what are you working on, Gene?
暂时在拍苏格兰舞剧
At the moment, Scotch.
我找到个茶杯，茶杯可以吗？
I found a cup. Will a cup be all right?
-酒杯好点 -酒杯
- I'd prefer a glass. - A glass.
你竟然不辞而别
You know, you left without saying goodbye.
这可不像你的作风 一点不像我心目中的你
That's not like you, not that I have slightest idea what you're like.
找到了，来
Success at last. See, a... Here we go.
你倒酒的水平看来下降了
Your skill as a bartender seems to have deteriorated.
-你紧张了？ -不，只是…
- Are you nervous? - Yes. No. I'm...
为什么紧张呢？ 上帝，这里闻起来像个酒吧
Why should I be nervous? My God, it's gonna smell like a saloon in here.
-这是什么？ -一首倾诉我爱你的诗
- What is it? - It's a poem telling you that I love you.
倾诉我不会霸占和嫉妒你的诗
And that I won't be possessive and I won't be jealous.
你想和谁上床就上床 和谁过就和谁过
And you can sleep with whoever you want, live with whoever you want.
我会照你说的做 我真想杀了你，但我办不到
I'll do anything that you say. I'd like to kill you, but I can't.
你可以为所欲为…
So you can do whatever you want to,
就是不能见我
except not see me.
或者在演独角戏期间抽烟
Or smoke during the monologue.
尤金，杰克和我都没对外宣布…
Gene, Jack and I, we haven't told anyone yet
我们觉得太尴尬了
because we were too embarrassed.
可是…
But
我们结婚了
we're married.
杰克和我结婚了
Jack and I got married.
-真是尴尬 -是的
- That is embarrassing. - Yes. Isn't it?
虽然感觉很蠢，但是我们想结婚
We felt very silly, but we wanted to do it.
一切都会好的，我们会齐心协力
And it's gonna be good. We're gonna work together.
一起渡过我们的时光
We're gonna spend all our time together.
所以我们租下了这所房子
That's why we took a lease on this place,
这样我们就不用回城里住了
so we wouldn't have to go back to the city.
这是否意味着我们要欺骗感情？
Does this mean that we have to cheat?
或者是自由和独立的婚姻？
Or is this a free and independent marriage?
-尤金 -你这个波特兰臭婊子
- Gene. - You're a lying Irish whore from Portland
竟然利用我，让杰克娶你
and you used me to get Jack Reed to marry you.
不，我没有
No, I didn't.
我只想和你做普通朋友，尤金
I just want us to be friends, Gene.
真是高尚，这种角色适合你，对吗？
Oh, how genteel. That would be a good role for you, wouldn't it?
“路易丝与杰克和尤金”
"There's Louise with Jack and Gene.
“尤金为她而疯狂，但杰克不知道”
"He's crazy about her, but Jack doesn't know.
“可怜的杰克和可怜的尤金为她心碎”
"Poor Jack. Poor Gene. What a heartbreaker she is."
你真是会伤男人的心，路易丝
What a heartbreaker you are, Louise.
对不起
I'm sorry. I'm...
他在哪？
Where is he?
华盛顿
Washington.
雷德太太
Well, Mrs. Reed,
我还是照你说的做，你想让我干什么？
I'll do whatever you say. What do you want me to do?
祝福我们
Wish us well?
我祝福…
I wish you well.
你和杰克
You and Jack.
《草叶集》
杰克！
Jack!
上帝
Oh, God.
这段时期，我不知道她是否…
I'm not sure whether she had an affair
和尤金・奥尼尔有私情
with Eugene O'Neill or not during this time.
没有人知道
And nobody seemed to know. Or...
反正这是他们自己的事
It was nobody's business, anyway, so...
我不清楚当时的情况是怎样
I don't know what that situation was.
据说她与雷德和奥尼尔…
The report was that she and Reed and O'Neill
是三角恋
had a mnage ?trois.
杰克，这是…
Jack, what... What is...
天哪！
Oh, God! I swear...
我们热爱美国！
...that we love America!
热爱她的大山和森林…
We love her mountains, her forests...
法国军队发生了叛乱
There were mutinies in the French army,
前线也发生多起叛变
there were mutinies in various parts of the front.
然后在1917年，装备简陋的军队
And then, in 1917, the troops, poorly armed,
缺衣少食地回到了俄国…
poorly equipped, poorly clothed, went back to Russia
想与沙皇谈判
to talk it out with the czar.
当他们回到俄国时，沙皇下台了
And when they got through, there wasn't any czar.
俄国大革命
Revolution in Russia.
那是1917年的春天
This was the spring of 1917.
我好兴奋
And I became so excited
在长凳上欢呼雀跃
that I zigzag-jumped the benches
还冲出了公园
as we walked out of the park.
年轻的我当时高兴极了
Oh, I was so happy as a young boy.
人民取得了革命胜利
Revolution, the people take over,
推翻了沙皇！
down with the czar!
我自然感到高兴
Naturally, I was happy.
你是不是把政治模糊化了？
Well, haven't you made the politics a little nebulous here?
-模糊化？ -就是不清晰
- What do you mean "nebulous"? - Unclear...
-怎样才叫清晰？ -我觉得不清晰
- How can you say they're unclear? - Well, they're unclear to me. I...
为何我一定要…
Why am I necessarily attempting
尝试去定义特定人群的政见呢？
to define the politics of a specific group of people?
这又不是我说的，这太过度单纯化了
It isn't what I said. I think it's a vast oversimplification.
个人观点而已
Oh, it's just an opinion.
要是你复印下来…
You know, if you made carbons of these,
我就把它们带上火车
I could take them on the train with me.
1916年，威尔逊因反战…
Wilson, of course, was elected on the platform of
而获得当选
"Keep us out of war" in 1916.
但是1917年，威尔逊竟出尔反尔
But in 1917, Wilson reversed himself
对德宣战
and declared war against Germany.
当时他的使命是保全世界民主
The mission at that time was to make the world safe for democracy.
雷德说过…
Reed said,
这是为民主而战吗？那么民主何在？
"This is a war for democracy? Where is the goddamn democracy?"
要是人类真的不想战争 战争早就停止了
If men really disapproved of war, dear, we'd have stopped wars years ago.
人类喜欢战争，一向如此
Men like wars. Always have.
于是人们穿上军装奔赴战场
So they all went and got little uniforms, went to war.
-祖国参战了！ -是的
- My country is at war! - Yes.
所以今天，我也参战了！
And so today, I, too, am at war!
我叫杰克・雷德，来自纽约
My name is Jack Reed, I'm from New York.
这不是我想要的战争 我才不会参战！
This is not my war, and I'm not gonna have anything to do with it!
好了…
All right. All right.
好了，大家
All right, folks.
当然当时很多人都有反战情绪
There was a lot of anti-war feeling, of course.
但我们没有一个反对战争 没有一个是真心反战的
We had no one against the war. There wasn't a soul against the war.
我并非说我们要批评工人的不觉悟
Well, I'm not talking about saying it to the workers any other way.
而是我们要怎样打动他们？
How do we move them?
对，我们如何组织他们？
Right. How do we organize them?
社会党…
The Socialist Party...
美国社会党不值得一屑
The Socialist Party of America is nothing to sneeze at.
你们以为社会党会当政吗？
You think the Socialist Party is going to take a position?
你们是赤色分子吧？
You boys are Reds, aren't you?
社会党没有用的，杰克，对吗？
The Socialist Party is useless. Jack, is that right?
这是事实…杰克？
Now, that's the truth. Jack?
美国参战了
The United States is at war.
你的朋友在跟你说呢
Your friends are talking to you.
如果全世界的工人联合起来 他们就可以阻止战争…
If the workers of the world act together, they can stop the war. And I'm not...
这家伙连撒出来的尿都是红的
This one even pisses red.
你满世界乱跑，肾脏不病发才怪
You ran around saving the world until your kidney acted up again.
真是“聪明”
Very intelligent.
四处跑去演讲…
And you're gonna keep running around making speeches
最后却回到了医院里
until you wind up in the hospital. Brilliant.
再下去你就会失去肾脏 那就彻底完了
And then, you're gonna lose your kidney. Perfect.
哈瑞，政府给你多少好处 让你叫我闭嘴？
Harry, how much is the government paying you to keep me quiet?
随你怎么说
- Very funny. Keep laughing. - Yeah.
很疼，是吧？
That hurt, didn't it?
我老实告诉你吧…
Listen, I'm gonna tell you something.
你不能再这样继续下去了
You're not gonna be able to keep doing what you've been doing.
你的病情非常严重，会性命不保的
This is a serious condition. It could kill you.
哈瑞，我想知道…
Harry, look, I want to know if...
这会影响我要孩子吗？
Could this thing interfere with having children?
-当然会，你死了还怎么做爱？ -严肃点，哈瑞
- Yes. You cannot have sex if you die. - No, come on, Harry. Seriously.
你现在想要孩子？
Are you thinking about having children?
现在不要，但是我想知道…
Not at the moment, but I want to be able to...
路易丝谈起要孩子的事了？
Is Louise talking about it?
没有
No.
她嘴上不说…
Well, just because she isn't talking about it
并不代表她心里不想
it doesn't mean she isn't thinking about it.
别担心，要孩子和肾脏无关
Don't worry. You don't make babies with your kidneys.
我要你回家养病
Look, I'm gonna send you home to Louise.
躺在床上，让她照顾你
Tell her to keep you there, put you in bed,
给你吃药，我会给你药方的
give you lots of liquids. I'm gonna write it all down.
路易丝并不知道我的病情 我不想让她担心
Look, Louise doesn't know about this. And I don't want her to, okay?
-好 -你能给我帐单吗？
- Fine. - So, can you give me my bill here?
-我不想把帐单寄回家 -你有钱吗？
- I don't want it sent to the house. - Do you have any money?
现在没有
Not at the moment.
那你怎么买单？回家吧
Then why the hell should I give you a bill? Go home.
我坚信社会主义与和平是分不开的
It is my belief that socialism and peace are inseparable.
我再次重申，社会党坚决反对…
And I reiterate that the Socialist Party will stand firmly behind
美国参与这场战争！
its resolution to oppose American involvement in this war!
主席先生，我是波士顿的代表 路易斯・佛拉纳
Mr. Chairman, Louis Fraina, Local Boston.
主席团承认波士顿的代表
The chair recognizes the delegate from Boston.
我还是想知道…
And I still want to know
我们会采取什么具体的行动反战
what specific action we are going to take against the war.
您的解决方法固然好
Your resolution is all very nice,
但是它能救命吗？我认为不能
but will it stop even one boy from being killed? I don't think so.
…被污蔑为不爱国的表现
...stigmatized as unpatriotic.
摆在我们面前的任务非常艰巨
The task that confronts us is difficult.
希望我们可以正确对待
Let us hope that we can handle it properly.
什么意思？
What's that supposed to mean?
愚蠢！
Stupid!
我想知道社会党是否会招兵买马
I'd like to know if the Socialist Party is gonna fight conscription or not.
-我也想知道 -请这位代表自报家门
- That's what I'd like to know. - Will the delegate identify himself?
我不是代表，主席先生 我叫约翰・雷德
I am not a delegate, Mr. Chairman. My name is John Reed,
是《大众》杂志的记者
I write for the magazine The Masses,
我想知道社会党是否会 组织示威游行…
and I want to know if the Socialist Party is gonna organize demonstrations...
抱歉，雷德先生 您在这里没有发言权
I'm sorry, Mr. Reed. You have no credentials here.
这里只有代表能发言，记者不能
Now, this floor is reserved for delegates, not journalists.
主席先生，社会党是否已准备好…
Mr. Chairman, is the Socialist Party prepared
-上台当政？ -闭嘴！
- to take a position on the draft or not? - Hey, shut up!
抱歉，雷德先生，您没有发言权
I'm sorry, Mr. Reed. You have no credentials.
让他说完
Let him speak, will you?
雷德先生，你想参与政党事务是吗？
Mr. Reed, you're getting into party politics, eh?
我只是想当好一名记者 主席先生…
I'm just trying to be a journalist. Mr. Chairman...
托洛茨基也是这样 看看俄国发生的大事吧
So is Trotsky. Let us see what happens in Russia.
你为何不加入社会党？ 我们需要像你这样的英才
Why don't you join the Socialist Party? We need good people like you.
俄国发生了翻天覆地的变化
Big things are happening in Russia.
骇人听闻的是 社会党却支持血雨腥风
As appalling as it may seem to see socialists supporting bloodshed,
对于战争期间支持政府…
I can understand the necessity of supporting one's government
我能理解其必要性
during times of war.
我们所面临的任务异常艰巨！
The task that confronts us is a giant!
我们必须继续反战！
In that, we must continue our opposition!
-我们得给狗起个名字 -它有名字
- We have to give this dog a name. - Well, she has a name.
它的名字怎么了？
What's the matter with her name?
-家里的东西我都找不到 -我可不想一直叫狗狗
- I can't find anything in this house. - I'm not going to call a dog "Dog."
要是它是小孩，你总不能叫它“人”吧？
I suppose if she were a baby, you'd wanna call her "Person."
不是，那就叫它杰克吧
Not really. I think I might wanna call her "Jack."
不好
No. No. Bad.
我老是找不到东西
See, now this is why I can't find anything.
你把东西到处乱放
You put things anywhere.
狗狗！
Dog! Dog!
它还没有被驯化
She's still not housebroken.
要是它趴下，你得把它拉开
You got to grab her when she squats like that,
把它拉出去，没错
and then take her outside. That's right.
等它出去之后，你得给它奖品
And then when she goes, you've got to give her a reward.
好吧，坐好，狗狗
All right. Now, stay, Dog.
晚餐吃大蒜吗，亲爱的？
Are we having garlic for dinner, honey?
不…
No, no, no.
怎么了？我放的大蒜太多了吗？
Why? Why, do you think I'm using too much garlic?
我觉得沙司里边应该放一点
I thought I'd put a little in the sauce.
我对大蒜并不反感
Garlic doesn't bother me.
-那是尤金的信 -对不起，我不是有意的
- That's from Gene. - Sorry. I didn't mean to read it.
我都没反应过来是什么
I didn't realize what it was.
他去年10月给的我 之后就没见面了
He gave it to me in October. I haven't seen him since.
-你不用解释 -我不是解释
- You don't have to explain. - I'm not explaining.
-我只是想告诉你这已经结束了 -路易丝
- I'm just telling you it's over. - Louise, look.
我不指望你什么事都告诉我
I don't expect you to tell me everything you do.
如果要跟我说，就请你说实话
What about if you tell me something, just tell me the truth?
-杰克，我已经不和他见面了 -别这样，路易丝
- Jack, I haven't seen him. - Don't do that, Louise.
别跟我说尤金六七个月前给了你 一封情书之后…
Don't tell me that Gene gave you a love poem six or seven months ago,
你就一直没有和他见面
but you put it in a book and you haven't seen him since.
我不在乎你见没见他
I don't care whether you've seen him or not.
-我在乎的是不坦诚 -我明白了
- I just care about dishonesty. - Oh, I see.
你不在乎我和别的男人有私情
You don't care that I had an affair with another man,
你只在乎不坦诚？现在是谁不坦诚
you just care about dishonesty? Look who's being dishonest.
你在乎，太在乎了 甚至都不屑一顾
You care. You care so much, you won't even talk about it.
-你甚至都不提… -想理论吗？我来跟你理论
- You won't even mention... - Wanna talk? I'll talk about it.
你想开诚布公吗？
You want to be honest about it?
要是我不想坦诚的话…
If I didn't wanna be honest about it,
我会愚蠢到把他给我的情书…
do you think I'd be silly enough to leave a poem he gave me
藏在沃尔特・惠特曼的书里吗？
lying around in the house in a book of Walt Whitman?
为什么不行呢？
Why not Whitman?
相信尤金一定会心安理得的
I'm sure Gene would feel right at home in that company.
不，你一点都不在乎
Oh, no. You don't care.
我为什么要在乎你和谁上床？
Why the hell should I care that you slept with somebody else?
你以为我不在乎？
Do you think I haven't?
我不赞成每次和别人上床…
I don't think we have to report to each other
我们都要互相通报，那毫无意义
every time we go to bed with somebody. It doesn't mean anything.
那不意味着我对你的爱就少一点
It doesn't mean that I love you any less.
和尤金上床会让你对我的爱少一点吗？
Do you love me any less 'cause you went to bed with Gene?
这有什么区别？
What difference does it make?
我不赞成撒谎，仅此而已
I just don't think we should lie about it. That's all.
-谁？ -什么谁？
- Who? - What do you mean, "Who?"
-是谁？ -什么是谁？
- Who was it? - Who was what?
那个人是谁？
Who was it?
你想要名单吗？这毫无意义
What do you want, a list? It doesn't mean anything.
路易丝
Louise.
-你干什么？ -不知道
- What are you doing? - I'm not sure.
-我想知道你要去哪 -不想说
- I wanna know where you're going. - I don't want to talk about it.
-那我想说 -那你就说个够吧
- Well, I wanna talk about it. - You said it all, Jack.
什么？难道我们还没说上百次吗？
What? What did I say now that we both haven't said 100 times?
请把我的来信转到约翰・惠勒…
Please forward my mail to John K. Wheeler,
惠勒贝尔集团那里
Wheeler Bell Syndicate.
早上我会叫人来搬我剩下的东西
I'll have someone pick up the rest of my things in the morning.
难道两个人一起生活…
Didn't we say that people had to give each other freedom
-不是彼此都有自由吗？ -我们说的东西多了
- if they were gonna live together? - We said a lot of things.
我还以为我们没有那么霸道
I thought we weren't going to be possessive.
-我还以为你爱我！ -谁说我不爱你了？
- I thought you loved me! - Who says I don't?
你只爱你自己！根本不爱我！
You love yourself! Me, you fuck!
你只有不出轨时才会爱我
When you're not fucking other people, that is!
自由？你的意思是 要我和你一样毫不在乎尤金
Freedom? You mean I should just be like you and not give a damn, is that...
你和尤金上床有没想过我们？
Is that what fucking Gene means? You don't give a damn about us?
我不会收拾行李的，我想知道你去哪
I'm not packing my bag. I wanna know where you're going.
-走开… -你上哪？
- Get out of my... - Where you going?
-走开… -你不能…
- Get out of my... - You're not going...
走开！滚开！
Get away! Get out of my way.
-到底有多少个？ -得了吧，路易丝
- How many were there? - Come on, Louise.
你根本就不知道如何一起生活
You don't know the first thing about what living together means.
走吧，我知道你去哪
Go ahead. I know where you're going.
原以为你需要人一起生活 但是我错了
I thought you needed someone to share your life with. But I was wrong.
你只想每天成为人们关注的焦点
As long as you get your two shots of limelight every day.
你什么都不缺
You don't need a thing.
下地狱吧！你们俩都下地狱去吧！
You go to hell! Both of you!
当时和路易丝・拜伦有私情…
It could possibly have been a matter of prestige, you know,
是一件相当有面子的事
to say that you had an affair with Louise Bryant.
我一直都不奢望…
I haven't been spared
有哪个男人和我有私情
the legends about men that are supposed to have had affairs with me,
因为我名如其人啊
because I was known by name.
根本就不可能有什么私情
Affairs which never occurred at all.
这很难说得清楚
It's very difficult to tell, you know.
最让人头疼的是…
Do you know there is nothing more bewildering
你收到一个疯子的情书，上面写着…
than when you get a letter from a loony who says,
“我们在威尼斯渡过了美妙的一周”
"That marvelous week we spent in Venice."
-对 -每两年都会发生这种事
- Yeah. - And it happens about every two years.
-是的 -非常特别
- Yes. - It's most extraordinary.
一天，我和我的姨妈在波特兰散步
One day, I was out walking with my aunt in Portland.
她很漂亮，身材很高挑
And she was quite something. She was six feet tall.
我问她…
And I said to her,
“路易丝的传闻是怎么回事？”
"What is all this ado about Louise?
“你觉得她怎样，贝丽姨妈？”
"What do you think of her, Aunt Belle?"
她说…
She said,
[1917年，巴黎] “她这人很有吸引力”
"Well, she had something that just appeals."
那就是我的故事
That's my story.
-感觉怎样？ -好多了
- How you feeling? - Oh, better.
-给你 -谢谢，哈瑞
- Here you are. - Oh. Thanks, Harry.
谢谢
Thanks.
幸好摘除得及时
Well, we got it out just in time.
但不知道另外一个肾的情况怎样了
But since God only knows what condition the one you've got left is in,
你最好善待它
you better treat it well.
你得告诉伊斯曼你午夜前必须休息
That means, tell that goddamn Eastman you got to be in bed by midnight.
要是被感染的话，到时就真的没救了！
If you get an infection now, that's it! Absolutely no salt!
“亲爱的杰克 知道你好点了我深感欣慰”
"Dear Jack, I'm relieved you're feeling so well again.
“我问过巴黎的专家了”
"I talked to a specialist here in Paris.
“他说你可以过正常人的生活”
"And he said you can lead a perfectly normal life.
“希望你不要停止写作”
"I hope you're not neglecting your writing.
“请不要浪费精力…”
"Please don't spend your energy
“去捕风捉影”
"getting caught up in things you can't afford."
“亲爱的杰克，随附上我的作品”
"Dear Jack, I'm enclosing a piece I've written
“是描述一个志愿救护车司机的”
"on a volunteer ambulance driver
“他来自纽约警局”
"from the New York City Police Department.
“还有，请不要再问我是否可以过来找我”
"Also, please don't keep asking me if you can come over here.
“那样会让我认为你没有…”
"It just makes me think you have no..."
“亲爱的杰克，惠勒对我的作品很满意”
"Dear Jack, yes, Wheeler's very happy with my work.
“这里的生活如火如荼，我没有时间…”
"Life here is so hectic and exhilarating that I don't have a minute..."
“亲爱的杰克，请不要担心，我很好”
"Dear Jack, don't worry, I'm well.
“只是要不停满足惠勒的创作要求”
"My only problem is keeping up with Wheeler's demands for more stories."
“写一系列的头条时事通讯《法国来信》”
"...serial newsletter under the heading, 'Letters from France.'
“请不要向任何人提起”
"Please don't mention this to anyone.
“我答应过惠勒，我不会告诉你任何事”
"I promised Wheeler I wouldn't say anything to you."
“亲爱的杰克，我想我的作品 通过了惠勒的审核”
"Dear Jack, I feel I've really grown through my work for Wheeler,
“所以没有理由为我本人担忧”
"and there's no reason to worry about my being here alone."
布尔什维克，桑迪，布尔什维克人！
Bolsheviks, Sandy. The Bolsheviks!
天哪，要是布尔什维克介入，桑迪
Jesus Christ, if the Bolsheviks get in, Sandy,
你大可亲吻自己的屁股拜拜了
you can just bend right over and kiss your ass goodbye.
因为他们会让俄国退出战争
Because they'll pull Russia right out of the war.
撤出东线战场，他们会退出
Right off the Eastern Front. They quit, that's all.
彼得，布尔什维克不成气候的
Pete, the Bolsheviks are small potatoes.
俄国不会袖手旁观的
Russia isn't gonna get out of the war.
你想看到香谢丽舍大道上的 凯旋门那里…
You want to walk down the Champs-Elys闲s someday
出现五十万德国大军吗？
and see 500,000 Krauts come barreling out of Fouquet's?
你最好希望布尔什维克成气候吧
You better hope that the Bolsheviks are small potatoes.
再来一杯，侍应！
Now, let's have another drink. Waiter!
侍应，每人再来一杯酒
Waiter, another round here.
天哪，是小爱玛！
Hey! Oh, God. It's Red Emma, Jr!
快过来
Hey, come over here!
说大声点，彼得 隔壁的人听不到
Speak up, Pete, speak up. They can't hear you in the next room.
-你好啊，杰克 -见到你很高兴
- How are you, Jack? - Good to see you.
老天，摘除肾脏后你瘦了起码二十磅
God. You look 20 pounds lighter since you lost that kidney.
-是吗？ -我打赌你只摘除了一个吧
- Oh, yeah? - I bet you only piss about half as much.
是的，通常都是两个的 来杯汽水
Yeah, but twice as often. Sarsaparilla.
杰克，布尔什维克能打倒克伦斯基吗？ (俄国社会革命领袖)
Jack, can the Bolsheviks overthrow Kerensky?
你还是去找个公正的观察员问问吧
Okay. Why don't you ask an impartial observer?
杰克，你到底为什么反对战争呢？
Goddamn it, Jack. What the hell you got against this war anyway?
该死，你为何不把威尔逊 连同斧头一起埋了呢？
Shit, why don't you bury the hatchet with Wilson?
重新回到报社吧，我们想看你的大作
Get back into print so we can all read some decent writing, you know.
-为大作干杯 -你为什么都能干杯
- I'll drink to that. - You'll drink to anything.
没错，见到你很高兴
Well, that's right, too. It's good to see you.
真是太高兴了，路易丝怎样？
Jesus Christ. It's good to see you. Goddamn, how's Louise?
不大好吧？
Not so good.
-她很好 -把我的话转告她…
- She's good. - Tell her from me that I said
约翰・惠勒根本就不会欣赏她的作品
that John Wheeler wouldn't know a story if it fell right on top of him.
杰克，你到底在干嘛？
I'll tell you. Hey, Jack, what are you doing?
到底在干嘛？你让他们抓狂
What the hell are you doing? You're driving them crazy.
你意识到了吗？
You realize that?
他们还以为你是德国佬呢！
They think you're some kind of goddamn German!
我喜欢！喜欢死了！
I love it! Goddamn, I love it!
对他们口诛笔伐，杰克
Give them hell, Jack. Give them hell.
-是要加冰的汽水吗？ -是的，谢谢
- Is that a sarsaparilla with ice? - Yeah, thanks.
没错，就是加冰的汽水
You bet your sweet patoosie, that's sarsaparilla with ice.
约翰・惠勒为什么不会欣赏？
Why wouldn't John Wheeler know a story if it fell on him?
因为约翰・惠勒是个傻子
John Wheeler's a dumbbell, that's why.
他人是很厉害
No, he's all right.
我只是不想看到路易丝受伤而已
I just hate to see Louise get hurt. That's all.
这话什么意思？
What are you talking about?
老天
Jesus Christ.
别告诉她是我说的，好吗？
Don't tell her that I told you. All right?
告诉我什么？
Told me what?
本・帕森斯告诉我 惠勒不得不让她走人
Well, Ben Parsons told me that Wheeler had to let her go
因为她的作品惠勒根本不用
because she hadn't turned anything in that he could use,
除了那个关于…
other than some story about a cop
警察志愿者司机的作品之外
that went over there to drive a police department ambulance.
-他让她走人？ -炒了她
- He let her go? - Fired her.
-你何时听说的？ -几个星期前
- When did you hear that? - A couple of weeks ago.
不是，一个月前 一个半月前
No, it was a month. More than a month and a half ago.
杰克，惠勒就是个混蛋
Oh, look, Jack, Wheeler's a goddamn moron.
叫她不必为解雇的事感到惭愧
Tell her she shouldn't feel ashamed about being fired.
-回头见 -怎么了，杰克？
- I'm gonna see you later, huh? - Jack, what's the matter?
我也被解雇了，大家都被解雇了
Hell, we've all been fired. I've been fired.
为解雇干杯
Hell, I'll drink to it.
想象一下，6千5百万大军…
Imagine, 65 million
去打仗
go to war. Right?
一千万人阵亡
10 million die.
一千万人成为孤儿
10 million become orphans.
2千万人伤残
20 million become maimed, crippled, or wounded.
欧洲大灾难肆虐
You had catastrophe in Europe.
欧洲大屠杀肆虐
You had a holocaust in Europe.
你有转变的雄心壮志
You had a desire for change.
在当时革命情绪…
Who can stop them
异常高涨的时候，谁能阻止战争？
when there was such a revolutionary sentiment? Huh?
谁来阻止？
Who could stop them?
看来我要买一台新的打字机了…
You know, I think I'm gonna have to get a new typewriter...
-你怎么… -怎么了？
- What are you... - What?
你气色不错，完全康复了吗？
You look fine. Are you all right now?
人不需要两个肾的
Oh, God, yes. Nobody needs two kidneys.
第二个只是摆设
The second one's just for show.
对不起，你来得不大是时候
Sorry, this isn't a very good time.
他们要把我转移到 另一个通讯中心
They're moving me to another communications center.
现在我没时间和你叙旧了
So, I'm just not going to be able to talk to you right now, Jack.
能出去谈一会儿吗？就一会儿
Could we just go out here a second? Just for a second?
-我要去俄国了 -是嘛？你应征了吗？
- Look, I'm on my way to Russia. - Oh, really? Have you enlisted?
开玩笑
Very funny.
我知道你在这里干得很出色
I know you're doing work here that's good,
我也看了你的救护车作品，写得很棒
'cause I read the ambulance piece and I thought that was good.
-谢谢 -我知道你在写书
- Thank you. - And I know you're working on your book
我知道它对你很重要
and I know how important that is to you.
要是你想在适当时候…
But you got to have enough sense
在适当地点成为一名优秀记者…
if you're trying to build up your reputation as a journalist,
你就得增强你的使命感
to be in the right place at the right time.
-谢谢你的建议 -这个适当的地点就是俄国
- I appreciate your advice. - Well, the place to be now is Russia.
-谢谢，我会记住的 -现在是乱世，他们坚持不了多久
- Thank you. I'll remember that. - Louise, it's chaos. They can't last.
6个月内已经上台三个临时政府了
They're in their third provisional government in six months.
知道意味着什么吗？ 意味着另一场革命即将爆发
You know what that means? It means there might be another revolution.
工人阶级放弃工厂，士兵放弃前线
The workers are deserting the factories, the army's deserting the battlefronts.
流放的人都回来了 犹太人，无政府主义者，社会党
The exiles are all coming back. The Jews, the anarchists, the socialists.
所有的人都回来了
All of them are going back, only this time
这次才可能会成大气候
it might be the real thing.
如果俄国爆发真正的工人革命
And if they have a real workers' revolution in Russia,
德国就会相继爆发，一旦德国爆发…
they'd have one in Germany, and if they had one in Germany,
-全世界都会爆发 -有火柴吗？
- it could happen all over the world. - Got a match?
路易丝，然后就是战争结束
Louise, that'd be the end of the war.
你不必跟我说俄国发生的事
You don't have to tell me what's happening in Russia.
-我看过报纸了 -跟我走吧
- I read the papers. - Well, come with me.
作我的同志，不是别的身份
As a colleague, I'm not talking about anything else.
我们一起前往彼得格勒
Come with me as a colleague. You ought to be in Petrograd.
是吗？你在纽约也是这么说的！
Oh, yeah? Well, that's what you said about New York!
-我那时是对的 -不，这里有我的事业
- I was right about New York. - No, I have work I'm doing here.
我的事业也是…
And I happen to think my work is...
是很重要，但没有俄国的事业重要
It is important. But it's not important as what you could be doing in Russia.
我想跟你作搭档，一起奋斗
I wanna work together. As partners.
我不要搭档，我想去俄国就一个人去
I don't want a partner. And if I wanted to go to Russia, I'd go alone.
-我不会让你带我去 -路易丝
- I wouldn't need you to take me. - Louise.
你一个柔弱女子 不适宜单独前往俄国这种乱世
Russia is not the safest place in the world for a woman to be alone.
你能成为一名出色记者 但那并不意味着…
You may be a hell of a journalist. But that doesn't mean...
路易丝，我们要走了
Louise, we'd better hurry along.
要转移了？
So, moving you out of here, huh?
是的，我要去采访普拉默将军
Yes. I've been promised an interview with General Plumer.
我也得走了
Well, I've got to run along myself.
-对不起，我时间匆忙 -不，我不想留下你
- Sorry I don't have any time. - No. I don't want to keep you.
只是想…座位已经预约了
I just... Look, the seat's already reserved.
你这是浪费钱财，杰克，我不要
You've wasted your money, Jack. I don't want it.
你可以改日期自己去 什么时候去都行
Change the date. Go by yourself. You can use it whenever you want to.
坚持自己的创作
Keep up the good work.
杰克
Jack.
祝好运
Good luck.
你也是
Yeah, you, too.
出租车在等我
I got a taxi waiting.
杰克！杰克・雷德！
Jack! Jack Reed!
-我是乔・沃斯基 -你好吗？
- Joe, Joe Volski. - How are you?
很好，你也去彼得格勒？
Oh, fine, fine. Are you going to Petrograd, too?
-是的 -太好了！
- Yes. Yeah. - Fine. Wonderful!
形势真是风云变幻，你一个人吗？
Great things are happening. Are you traveling by yourself?
-应该是吧 -那我搬过去坐
- I think I am. - Well, then I'll switch.
我们在芝加哥见面过
We met in Chicago.
你真是个大演讲家！
Boy, oh, boy. Were you a speaker!
不记得我了吗？
You don't remember me, eh?
不是的
Well, it's not that.
-可能是因为帽子 -我的帽子？
- Maybe I just... Maybe it's the hat. - My hat?
对，你戴上这顶别致的帽子 我认不出了
Yeah. Maybe I just don't recognize you in this particular hat.
我现在是化妆成老百姓的革命者
Oh, then I'm a revolutionary returning in disguise.
等到革命胜利，我给你买顶新帽子
Well, comes the revolution, I'll buy you a new hat.
-你好像在学俄语 -是的，正在努力学
- I see you're studying Russian. - Yeah. I'm trying to.
知道吗？
Know what?
-什么？ -我是说…
- What? - I mean,
你可以问我这个俄国通
ask me anything you want in Russian.
谢谢，我会记住的
Thank you. I'll keep that in mind.
我看看…
Let's see...
抱歉，打搅了，我有话要说
Excuse me. Excuse me, now here's the thing.
我不接受你提议的话就太愚蠢了 但我有条件
I'd be a goddamned fool not to take you up on this offer. So, here's what I want.
我要在我自己的报道上签我的名字
I want to sign my own name to my own stories
我不要联名
and I don't want to use a double byline.
我要自行安排自己的时间和活动
I want to be responsible for my own time and my own actions.
我要别人称呼我拜伦小姐 而非雷德夫人
I want to be referred to as Miss Bryant, and not as Mrs. Reed,
我要记下我们所有的花费…
and I want to keep an account of every cent we spend
以便我还给你
so that I can pay you back.
还有，我不会再跟你上床
Now, I assume you know that I'm not going to sleep with you,
所以，你不要对我有非分之想
so just don't confuse the issue by bringing it up.
完了
That's it.
-好 -好
- Fine. - Good.
喜欢意大利香肠吗？
You like salami?
有个人说“等一下，我得回去”
He says, "Wait a minute, I have to go back.
“我把假牙落在桌子上了”
"I forgot my teeth on the table."
另一个人说“别管你的假牙了”
He says, "Hell with your teeth!
“你以为天上会掉馅饼下来给你咬吗？”
"What do you think, they're bombarding with sandwiches?"
革命胜利后我给你买新帽子
After the revolution, you'll buy me a new hat.
非常感谢，我会记住的
Thank you very much. I'll keep you by your word.
对了，你听过这个笑话没？一个人…
By the way, did you hear this one? A man...
列宁问我“为什么留胡子？”
Lenin asks, "Why do you let your beard grow?"
我回答到“我想记得昨天吃了什么”
I says, "I want to remember what I ate yesterday."
这个比较难念，意思是“我不抽烟”
This is a hard word, but it means "I don't smoke."
好
Okay.
“你是家属吗？” 他说“不是，所以我才哭”
"Are you one of the family?" He said, "No. That's why I'm crying."
伐木营的工头想招工
There's a foreman of a logging camp, he's trying to hire a crew.
许多人在排队，都是牛高马大的汉子
You know, and he goes down a long line of very big men
他抓住了一个小个子
and he gets to a little man in the back
他问到 “你是什么人？到这来干什么？”
and he says, "Who the hell are you? What're you doing here?
“你不知道我要的是 一天能砍上百棵树的壮汉吗？”
"Don't you know that I need men who can chop down dozens of trees a day?
“你以前在哪干过活？”
"Where the hell have you ever worked before?"
小个子说 “我以前在撒哈拉森林干活”
And the little man says, "Well, I worked in the Sahara forest."
工头又问了 “你指的是撒哈拉沙漠吧？”
And the foreman says, "You mean the Sahara Desert."
小个子回答说“是的，那里砍完了！”
And the little man says, "Yes, sure, now!"
一名男子敲开了邻居的门…
A woman knocks at the door of her neighbor.
我没说过这故事吗？
I didn't tell you that?
一名女子说“我丈夫刚去世 我想卖掉他的夹克”
She says, "My husband just died. I want to sell his jacket."
他说“裤子怎么回事？”
He says, "What's the matter with the pants?"
她回答说“裤子我穿过了”
She says, "The pants, I wear."
俄国边境到了
The Russian border.
他已经打仗了三个月
He's already fighting for three months.
现在已经加入布尔什维克 不再打仗了
Now he joined the Bolsheviks and he's not going to fight anymore.
他不是怕死 军队里有很多布尔什维克人
I don't think he's afraid. There are many Bolsheviks in the army.
布尔什维克人会阻止战争
And the Bolsheviks will stop the war.
他今年才14岁
He's 14 years old.
显然共产党人想要和平
The Communists obviously wanted peace. Rightly so.
因为俄国正处于风雨飘摇的局势…
Because the country was completely unable to sustain a war.
到处是叛变和腐败
There was treason and there was corruption.
一切都是有目共睹
There was everything under the sun.
但那是不可能…
But certainly... There was certainly no possibility
操纵战争的
of conducting a war.
克伦斯基急于操纵战争
Kerensky was anxious to conduct it,
他甚至招募女兵上战场
produce some battalions of women who were going to go and fight.
杰克・雷德！
Jack Reed!
亚历克斯，你在这里干什么？
Alex, what the hell are you doing here?
-有人接你吗？ -没有
- You have someone to meet you? - No.
幸好我来了！
Then what luck I am here!
-洛丝？ -是的
- Lois? - Yes.
我是亚历克斯・冈博
Alex Gomberg.
-找地方长住吗？ -不，住酒店
- Looking for accommodation? - No. Just a hotel.
真走运，我知道一套闲置的公寓
More good luck. I know of an empty apartment.
有交通工具吗？没问题，跟我来
You have transportation? No problem. Follow me.
许多人都认为乌托邦的理念正在成熟
A lot of people had an idea that Utopia was growing up.
我本来该责备 这个前布尔什维克主义
I could not blame them for being pro-Bolshevik,
但是我没有
but I wasn't.
完全忽略俄国的人是…
The one person who was awfully ignorant about Russia
-碧翠丝・韦伯 -对，就是她
- was Beatrice Webb. - Yes, she was.
她真是无知
She didn't know a thing.
不要被街道上的宁静气氛所误导
Do not be misled by the quiet in the streets.
暗地里都剑拔弩张着呢
Underneath is great tension.
亚历克斯，克伦斯基政府 还能支撑多久？
Alex, how much time has the Kerensky government got left?
随时会垮台，布尔什维克就要罢工了
Any day now, the Bolsheviks will strike.
很美妙吧？
Fantastic, isn't it?
宁静的街头就是彼得格勒的中心
A quiet street, and yet we are in the heart of Petrograd.
给他四卢布
Give him four rubles.
杰克，洛丝，幸好有我在
Jack, Lois. Lucky for you, I am here.
是的，谢谢了
Yeah. Thanks. Thanks again.
只有一张床？是双人床
Only one bed? That's a double.
单人床！我就睡这里…
Single. That's a single! This is where I'II...
这里不错，我可以…
This is good for me. I can just...
好
Good.
我一点都不介意
I don't mind this at all.
他说这是起义，对吧？
He's calling for an insurrection, isn't he?
夜以继日
Day and night. Day and night.
“另一个起义会摧毁俄国”
"Another insurrection will ruin Russia."
“另一个起义会拯救俄国”
"Another insurrection will save Russia."
“战争在摧毁俄国”
"The war is ruining Russia."
“没有英格兰或者法国，俄国会孤立无助”
"Without England or France, Russia will be isolated."
“布尔什维克在摧毁俄国”
"The Bolsheviks are ruining Russia."
洛丝，幸好有我在
Lois, lucky for you, I am here.
我叫路易丝
Louise.
这一排是等面包的
- This is the line for bread. - Yes.
另一排是等鞋子的
There's another line for boots.
还有一排等卡片
And there is still another line for cards
凭卡片可以在两三个月内领到鞋子
on which they'll get the boots in two, three months.
排队领面包非得铲除掉沙皇才行吗？
Did we have to get rid of the czar to stand in line for bread?
-什么意思？ -不知道
- What does that mean? - I don't know.
沃斯塔尼意思是起义 “Kerensky”是指克伦斯基
Vosstanie means "Insurrection," and "Kerensky" means "Kerensky,"
布尔什维克尔是指布尔什维克
and Bolsheviki means Bolshevik.
所以我认为布尔什维克 是想通过起义…
So I think it calls for an insurrection by the Bolsheviks
反对克伦斯基政府和克尼洛夫奇
against the Kerensky government and the kornilovtsy.
-什么叫克尼洛夫奇？ -路易丝，我的俄语不流利
- What's a kornilovtsy? - Louise, I'm not that fluent in Russian.
要是他们看中你的文章
Look, if they buy this,
他们会把文章删减成四五百字，对吧？
they're gonna cut you down to 400 or 500 words, aren't they?
-你之前好像写了5千字 -你删减了哪里？
- That starts out like you got 5,000. - Where would you cut?
这里还有这里
I'd lose this. I'd lose this.
你的主线是什么？
But what's your lead?
我知道你想什么，你指的是中心思想
Oh, I know what you think. You think the strongman line.
我不认为你的这个中心思想…
Well, I just don't know if you're gonna take anybody's breath away
吸引不了读者，知道吗？
with that for a lead. You know?
没错，太长了，太空泛了
You're right. It's too long, it's too general.
中心思想是最好的主线
And the strongman line is the best lead.
有些事你也有自己的正确看法
You've been right about something else, too.
布尔什维克会让俄国远离战争
The Bolsheviks will take Russia out of the war.
-晚安 -晚安
- Good night. - Night.
“街上的话题是和平与面包”
"In the streets the talk is of peace and bread.
“克伦斯基两者都没能提供”
"Neither of which Kerensky has provided."
“大家都知道会有事发生”
"Everybody knows that something is going to happen,
“只是不知道什么事”
"but nobody knows just what."
什么事？
Yes?
对不起，我不会说俄语 我说英语
I'm sorry, I don't speak Russian. I'm English.
“彼得格勒夜不能眠”
"Petrograd does not sleep.
“晚上，争论越来越大声 人群越来越汹涌”
"At night, the arguments grow louder and the crowds thicken."
“谁都对克伦斯基不满”
"Nobody is satisfied with Kerensky.
“右派需要一个强人，左派需要和平”
"The far right wants a strongman, the far left wants peace.
“大家都对布尔什维克的举措拭目以待”
"Everyone waits to see what the Bolsheviks will do."
“描写布尔什维克领导人列宁很不容易”
"It is not easy to write fairly about the Bolshevik leader Lenin.
“他冰冷而专注，不容忍别人打搅”
"He is absorbed, cold, impatient of interruptions."
-你在这里发表社论了 -我从不发表社论
- You're editorializing here. - I never editorialize.
-结尾 -没错，删掉
- At the end. - You're right. Cut it.
我不明白的是…
What I don't understand is...
为什么删掉枪战的报道 它很精彩啊
Why did you take out the piece about the gunshot? It was very good.
-是不是精彩？ -是的
- It is good, isn't it? - Yeah.
放回去
Put it back in for me.
兹诺维耶先生 您还认为布尔什维克起义…
Mr. Zinoviev, do you still feel that the timing is wrong
不是时候吗？
for a Bolshevik insurrection?
“我在斯莫尔尼宫采访了兹诺维耶”
"I interviewed Zinoviev at Smolny.
“他一直和列宁在躲藏”
"He'd been in hiding with Lenin."
“已经躲藏了十年，并非一朝一夕”
...had another whole decade, less than a day.
“他的性格依然是躲躲闪闪的”
"His style is still that of a man in hiding.
“我们听到托洛茨基在斯莫尔尼宫的讲话”
"We hear Trotsky speak at Smolny.
“如果列宁代表着思想 托洛茨基代表行动”
"If Lenin represents thought, Trotsky represents action.
“那他就是十足的煽动家”
"He is essentially an agitator."
“斯莫尔尼宫的会客厅济济一堂”
"The meeting hall at Smolny was packed. At one point,
“讲台上的人叫同志们不要吸烟”
"someone in the platform asked the comrades not to smoke,
“所有的人，包括抽烟的人，全都叫道…”
"and everybody, including the smokers took up the cry,
“同志们，不要抽烟！ 然后又继续抽烟”
"'Don't smoke, comrades! ' And then they went on smoking."
“此时，托洛茨基说 我们正试图避免起义”
"At the point Trotsky said, 'We are trying to avoid insurrection,
“但是，如果克伦斯基政府袭击我们”
"'but if the Kerensky government attacks us,
“我们将会以牙还牙”
"'we shall answer blow by blow,'
“场下的听众一片欢腾”
"the audience broke into wild cheers."
“列宁是一位怪异的大众领导人 天资聪颖”
"Lenin is a strange popular leader, a leader purely by virtue of intellect.
“毫无幽默感，从不妥协”
"Colorless, humorless, uncompromising,
“他没有托洛茨基强烈的个性”
"he seems to have none of Trotsky's force of personality
“也没有托洛茨基的演讲天赋 然而列宁依然成为了导师”
"or his gift for phrasemaking, and yet it is Lenin who is the architect."
克伦斯基是社会主义者？
Kerensky is some socialist, huh?
“沙皇的冬宫现在是克伦斯基政府所在地”
"The Winter Palace of the czar, where Kerensky's government holds office,
-“那里金壁辉煌…” -冬宫里静悄悄的
- "is vast and magnificent..." - "It is quiet in the Winter Palace.
“毫无罢工和停工的迹象”
"There's no sign here of the strikes and lockouts
“不像莫斯科和敖德萨” (苏联港市)
"that convulse Moscow and Odessa.
“交通运输并未瘫痪”
"No evidence that transportation is paralyzed,
“士兵们忍饥挨饿，城市里面包难求”
"that the army is starving and in the big cities, there is no bread."
“克伦斯基充满旧世界的温文尔雅 完全与列宁不同”
"Kerensky is full of old-world manners and charm, totally unlike Lenin."
“克伦斯基在采访中称 ”临时政府将继续执政
"'Provisional government will last,' Kerensky said during the interview,
“不管布尔什维克如何罢工”
"'in spite of the Bolsheviks.'"
“他看似在强烈抵抗”
"He seemed bitter, defensive."
“90万人自从1月1日以来无所事事”
900,000 men deserted since January the 1st.
那可是俄国军队人数的14%
That's 14% of the Russian army. I...
我在炖白菜，换换口味会好点
I'm sort of braising the cabbage. 'Cause I thought it'd be a nice change.
知道莱斯・威廉姆斯住的房子吗？
You know that house where Rhys Williams is staying?
一天晚上，那个银行家的女儿 歇斯底里地回来
Evidently, the banker's daughter came home in hysterics the other night,
因为电车司机称她为同志了
'cause some woman streetcar conductor called her "comrade."
晚餐过后，他们都投票
So after dinner, they all voted
喜欢德国的人 是喜欢布尔什维克人数的十倍
they preferred the Germans to the Bolsheviks by 10-to-one.
社会主义革命代表团要求英国大使…
Anyway, the Social Revolutionaries asked the British ambassador
不要宣布他们的造访
to please not to mention their visit,
因为他们已经被认为是极右派了
because they were already considered too far to the right.
这是一群一年前还看不到的人…
And you know, it's the same group of people
因为那时他们还是极左派
you couldn't even see a year ago, 'cause they were too far to the left.
卡萨维纳今晚跳舞
Karsavina is dancing tonight.
曼尼・科洛夫说卓别林将…
And, oh, Manny Komroff says that Charlie Chaplin will be...
杰克
Jack...
谢谢你带我来这里
Thanks for bringing me here.
他们会罢工吗？
Will they strike?
你会说英语吗？
Do you speak English?
-你会说英语吗？ -会
- Do you speak English? - Yes.
他们会罢工吗？
Will they strike?
-纽约人？ -是的
- New York? - Yes.
-知道布鲁姆大街吗？ -知道！
- You know Broome Street? - Yes!
能告诉我他在说什么吗？
I know, but can you tell me what he's saying?
-我在那里住过四年 -真的？他…
- I lived there four years. - Really? What's he...
他说什么？
What is he saying?
能告诉我他说什么吗？
Can you tell me what he's saying?
他说不罢工，罢工不对…
He says don't strike. He says it's not right
那样会让我们士兵 手无寸铁地在前线挣扎
to leave our Russian soldiers at Front without guns.
纽约到这里可是千里迢迢啊
You are a long way from New York.
他说我们的俄国士兵在前线…
He says that our Russian soldiers at the Front
也是罢工
are also strike.
所以他们才会撤离前线
That is why they're leaving the Front.
说什么？
What's that?
他说英法美三国的工人…
He said that the workers of England, France and America
将会独自打击德国
will be left alone to fight Germany.
告诉他，他根本不知道…
Tell him he doesn't know how many workers
有多少英法美的工人反对战争
in England, France and America are against the war.
你在纽约住过，告诉他
You lived in New York. Tell him that.
你说得对，美国人
You are right, American.
你继续说
Go ahead, you speak.
继续啊
Go ahead.
说说你们美国工人
Tell them about your American workers.
不，我不能讲话 我没有发言权
No, I can't speak here, I don't have any credentials to speak here.
-我是美国人… -发言权？什么发言权？
- I'm an American... - Credentials? What credentials?
这里每个人都有发言权
Everyone has credentials here.
他叫你讲话呢
He ask you to speak.
你说，我翻译
Speak. I translate.
我只想说，如果你们罢工…
I only want to say that if you strike,
美国工人就不会感到被出卖
the American workers will not feel betrayed.
他们在等待你们作出榜样
They're waiting for your example.
他们在等待你们作出领导
They're waiting for your leadership.
如果你们拒绝 为资本主义战争机器工作…
If you refuse to support the capitalist war machine,
他们将会跟随你们
they will follow your example.
如果全世界的工人阶级联合起来…
And if workers of the world stand together,
战争将会被阻止
the war can be stopped.
他们会支持你们并参加革命！
They support you and will join you in revolution!
“这是最后的斗争”
Then, comrades, come rally
“团结起来到明天”
And the last fight Let us face
“英特纳雄耐尔”
The Internationale
Unites the human race
“就一定要实现”
Then, comrades, come rally
“这是最后的斗争”
“团结起来到明天”
And the last fight Let us face
“英特纳雄耐尔”
The Internationale
“就一定要实现”
Unites the human race
就这样唱
That's how it goes.
[纽约，1918年] 搬运工！
Porter!
没收
Confiscate it.
周三我带到华盛顿去
I'll take it with me to Washington on Wednesday.
谁下的令？
On whose authority?
司法部长下的令
The authority of the Attorney General.
好，包起来
All right, pack it up.
-司法部长？ -美国司法部长
- Attorney General? - Attorney General of the United States.
颠倒了
That's upside down.
[美国海关] -路易丝 -麦斯
- Louise! - Max!
你好吗？
How are you?
嗨，麦斯
Max. Hi!
嗨
Hi!
天哪，路易丝，你气色真好
Oh, God, Louise. You look good!
你一定是很会保养吧
God, whatever you've been doing, you ought to bottle it.
谢谢
Oh, thank you.
他要写书，麦斯，我要给他做宣传
He's gonna write a great book, Max, and I'm gonna lecture while he's doing it
这样才能生活下去
so we can have something to live on.
不管我到哪宣传他都要写
And he's gonna write wherever I'm lecturing.
我们会回到克洛顿去
And then we're gonna go back to Croton
他要帮我编辑…
and he's gonna help me edit my collection of articles
女性解放运动的文章
on women in the Revolution,
就是说我们会互相帮助编辑
and then we're gonna help edit each other's books.
不再分开，麦斯 我们真的互相发誓了
No more separations. We've really promised each other, Max.
我们真的要过一辈子
We're really going to get down to living our own lives.
那里真是感人，麦斯 你应该去一趟
It's so moving. God, Max, you should've been there!
他们拿走了我的笔记 都是我写书用的
Well, they took my notes. Every goddamn note I have for my book.
他们能这么做吗？
Can they do that?
欢迎回家，走吧
Welcome home. Let's go.
走，我们去把你的笔记拿回来
Come on, come on. We'll get your notes back.
你要写书
You'll write your book.
发生了好多事，你们到底怎么回事？
A lot's been happening. Now what the hell is going on here, Jack?
你跟路易丝决定要幸福生活了？
I understand you and Louise have decided to be happy?
对于在一个正在战争中的国家而言…
It's a very difficult situation
这是一个很艰难的处境
for a country who is conducting a war,
当其中一个同盟爆发革命…
when one of its allies has a revolution
政府换届
and the government is changed.
最典型的就是俄国人退出
The thing that made the furor was that the Russians withdrew,
我们少了一个同盟
and we lost an ally.
我们以为俄国人会支持我们
We thought the Russians had gone back on us.
那时候，布尔什维克革命…
The Bolshevik Revolution, at the time,
是历史上最著名的罢工事件
was the most single striking event in the history of the times,
也是整个时代最著名的
of the whole era.
俄国社会彻底转型
The complete transformation of Russian society,
国家机器的权力…
and the taking over by the peasants and the workers
为工人与农民所掌握
of the machinery of the state.
这在历史上从未有过
It never had happened before in history.
“你是庄严的旧旗”
You're a grand old flag
“高高飘扬的旗帜”
You're a high flying flag
“永远在空中飘动”
And forever and e'er may you wave
“你是我热爱祖国的象征”
You're the emblem of The land I love
“自由与勇敢之家”
The home of the free and the brave
“每一颗心都真实地跳动”
Every heart beats true For the red, white and blue
“从未有过自夸与吹牛”
Where there's never a boast or brag
“忘掉旧的意识”
Should auld acquaintance be forgot
“注视庄严的旗帜”
Keep your eye on the grand old flag
1918年之前从未有过
Over There is not till 1918.
“那边，那边”
Over there, over there
“传话”
Send the word, send the word
“那边，北方佬正前来…”
Over there That the Yanks are coming...
你认识
You know that one.
另一个是《庄严旧旗帜》之后
But the other one after Grand Old Flag,
也许是之前的，“我是一个北方小混混”
or before, was I'm a Yankee Doodle Dandy.
“我是一个北方小混混”
I'm a Yankee Doodle Dandy
“北方小混混”
Yankee Doodle...
“真正的山姆大叔的侄子”
Real live nephew of my Uncle Sam
“生于7月4日”
Born on the 4th of July
“我有一个北方佬甜心”
I've got a Yankee Doodle sweetheart
“她是我的北方佬玩具”
She's my Yankee Doodle joy
“北方佬去伦敦都骑马”
Yankee Doodle went to London Just to ride the ponies
“我是北方佬小毛孩”
I am the Yankee Doodle boy
非常流行
That was a big hit.
-你相信上帝吗？ -什么？
- Do you believe in God? - I beg your pardon?
拜伦小姐，这是很简单的问题 你要我重复吗？
It's a simple question, Miss Bryant. Now do you want me to repeat it?
对不起，至少这时候是
I'm sorry, for a moment I thought
你问我是否相信上帝
you asked me if I believed there's a God.
我问得很简单
That is precisely what I asked you.
我一点都不知道
I see. Well, I have no way of knowing.
你是基督徒吗？
Are you a Christian?
我在天主教堂接受过洗礼
I was christened in the Catholic Church.
-那么现在你是基督徒了？ -应该是
- Well, are you a Christian now? - I suppose I am.
你相信上帝耶稣吗？
Do you believe in Our Lord Jesus Christ?
我相信耶稣的教导 我是否对魔力感到厌倦了？
I believe in the teachings of Christ. Am I being tried for witchcraft?
拜伦小姐，告诉我
Miss Bryant, tell me,
布尔什维克人中，是否没有正统 不畏惧上帝的基督徒？
are there no decent, God-fearing Christians among the Bolsheviks?
谁有必要做一个畏惧上帝 又是正统的基督徒？
Does one have to be God-fearing and Christian to be decent?
参议员，布尔什维克相信 这是种宗教，尤其是基督教
Senator, the Bolsheviks believe that it's religion, particularly Christianity,
这让俄国人民倒退了好几个世纪
that's kept the Russian people back for so many centuries.
-拜伦小姐 -如果你们谁去过俄国
- Miss Bryant... - lf any of you'd ever been to Russia
见到了农民，也许你们会赞同这一点
and seen the peasants, you might think they had a point.
参议员，就正统这点来说
On the subject of decency, Senator,
布尔什维克用一个口号取得了 政权战争的结束
the Bolsheviks took power with the slogan, "An end to the war."
6个月内，他们对俄国人民满口承诺
Within six months, they made good their promise to the Russian people.
1916年，美国总统去了俄国
Now, the present President of the United States of America
立场是无战争
went to this country in 1916, on a "no war" ticket.
6个月内，他就让我们卷入了战争
Within six months, he'd taken us into the war,
11.5万美国年轻人命丧他乡
and 115,000 young Americans didn't come back.
如果这是正统，畏惧上帝的基督徒行为
If that's how decent, God-fearing Christians behave,
那么我随时可能会做无神论者
give me atheists anytime.
参议员，在俄国，女人有投票权
By the way, Senator Overman, in Russia, women have the vote,
这个国家远远超乎你的想像
which is more than you can say for this country.
拜伦小姐
Miss Bryant,
你是否建议我们国家 也建立苏维埃政府？
do you advocate a Soviet government for this country?
不，我认为在这个国家行不通
No. In this country I don't think it would work.
赤色份子害怕吗？
In other words, you mean the Red scare?
是他们害怕，还是我们害怕？
They got scared, or we got scared?
不，我们不怕
No, we didn't get scared.
他们害怕工人会强大起来
They were afraid that the unions would grow in strength.
他们害怕美国激进分子的运动
A radical movement in America. They were scared.
是的
Oh, sure.
美国佬会怕得要死
The Americans, they were frightened to death by it, you know.
担心他们国家也会如此
That it could occur here.
当然，大家都怕得要命
Sure. Everybody was in mortal dread
怕政府抛弃他们
of the government descending on them.
那些FBI密探，等等群体
The FBI or whatever it was, don't you know.
我们必须揭露他们
We had to expose them.
一旦他们告诉了 美国人民什么是共产主义
And once they told American people what Communism was...
那么现在人们不可能跟 共产主义毫无关系
People won't have nothing to do with Communism now.
他们知道那是什么
They know what it is.
不过在当时，他们不知道 那是新事物
But then, they didn't know. It was a new thing.
公开的观念已经深入人心
Public opinion was solidly against anyone
他们对俄国革命一片好评
who had a good word for the Russian Revolution.
但路易丝是从自己的体会来谈的
But Louise was always communicating what she had experienced.
我带了毛毯来
I brought blankets, here,
还有厚外套
and a heavy coat, here.
还有咖啡
Chase and Sanborn.
手套
Gloves.
谢谢，杰克 其他人都只给我带了帽子
Thank you, Jack. Everyone else brought me hats.
路易丝捎来了她最好的，还有这个
And Louise sends you her best and this.
围巾，太好了
A scarf. Very kind.
时间到了
I'm afraid your time is up.
Well,
我们要继续战斗下去
we're going to keep fighting this.
你可否告诉麦斯 我想在杂志里刊登自己的照片？
Will you tell Max I'd like a picture of myself in the magazine?
我希望在照片下面写上“1919年受驱逐”
And under it, I would like the words, "Deported in 1919.
“这个世上最为强大国家的政府…”
"The government of the most powerful country in the world
“竟害怕这个女人”
"is afraid of this woman."
我们会救你出来的，埃玛
We're going to get you back, E.G.
革命需要你，我们会救你出去的
The revolution needs you. We're gonna get you back.
同志，我不会离开革命
Comrade, I'm not leaving the revolution.
要是在俄国，我也会加入革命
In Russia, I'll be joining it.
我迫切要求驱逐…
I urged the deportation of all
外来共产党员 所有的外来共产党员
alien Communists. All alien Communists.
有本国共产党员已经够受的了
It's bad enough having a Communist with us,
再加上外来共产党员就更要命了
but to have alien Communists who are not citizens,
他们宣布我们的政府形式 和共和制是无能的
denouncing our form of government and our republic
他们应该被驱逐
and everything else, they should be deported.
长久以来，我领导着一场大战
And I led a big fight on that for a long while.
当时的气氛不是很健康
It wasn't a very healthy atmosphere.
[路易丝生日快乐] 所以当约翰・雷德来的时候
So when John Reed came along,
他的发言我很喜欢
well, he was a voice of what I love.
他能够进入最有争议的话题
He was able to go into the most controversial subject of all,
共产主义，布尔什维克主义
Communism, Bolshevism.
他是公认的唯一能够做这类事的人
He was considered one of the rare persons who could do a thing like that.
他知道他站在了历史的新开端
He knew he was on the threshold of history,
他是这么写的
and he wrote it that way.
-这样翻… -杰克，我回来了
- A touch of this... - Jack, I'm back!
我在这里，亲爱的
I'm in here, honey.
今天我在李莱特家跟埃蒙和埃弗德谈过了
I talked to Edmund and Alfred today at Liveright's.
-今天真是收获不小 -别进来，亲爱的
- What a day it's turned out to be. - Stay out, honey! Stay out, stay out.
你在干什么？没事吧？
What are you doing in there? Is everything okay?
-要帮忙吗？ -不
- Can't I help? - No, no, no, no!
闻起来不错，是什么？
Sure smells good. What is it?
别进来，亲爱的 埃蒙说了什么？
Stay out, honey. What did Edmund have to say?
出去，亲爱的，埃蒙说了什么？
他说几个星期之后钢铁工人就要罢工
He said in a few weeks the steelworkers will strike.
他说至少有20万人，也许有30万
He thinks at least 200,000 of them, and maybe as many as 300,000.
他认为这次阻止不了他们了
But he doesn't think there's any stopping them this time.
是吗？太好了
Yeah? That's good.
你考虑要发表什么评论吗？
You still thinking about doing a piece on it? I am.
现在不好说，他说下一步要怎么办？
Well, I can't really talk now, but what does he say the next step is?
显然联邦政府会说 组织者一定是赤色分子
Evidently the federal government's saying the steel organizers are Reds.
所以，他们会成立一个调查局
So what they're doing is forming a bureau of investigation
调查破坏活动
just to look into subversive activity.
以及调查那些工会联盟领导人…
And you know, with all this talk about the leadership of the AF of L
与钢铁托拉斯的密谋
being in cahoots with the Steel Trust,
埃弗德问我是否会报道 世界产业工人组织
Alfred asked me if I was still gonna do the piece on the IWW.
我对埃弗德说，目前我不想再进一步
So I said, "Alfred, for the moment I don't want to go any further away
-我宁愿待在新泽西 -是嘛？
- "than New Jersey." - Really?
很好
Oh, that's good. That's good.
-只是… -很好
- Just... - Yeah, it is good.
你先坐，我马上来
Sit down. I'll just be a minute.
杰克，你在干什么？
Jack, what are you doing?
-你怎么把稿件交给了埃蒙？ -他会刊登的
- How did you leave it with Edmund? - He's gonna read the piece on Debs.
第一道菜
Okay, the first course.
-是吗？ -坐下
- Yeah? - Sit down.
坐下，闭上眼睛，坐下
Sit down and close your eyes. Sit down.
好了
Okay.
天哪
Oh, my.
天…
My...
吃吧
- Go ahead. - Oh.
怎么样？
What do you think?
真的？真好吃？
Really? You serious?
真的？感谢上帝 我刚才还打算烧烤呢
Really? Thank God. I was gonna flamb?them out here,
没想到肉自己在锅里烧着了
but the goddamn things flamb闲d themselves in the pan.
在革命运动发展的过程中…
He was certainly the main inspiration
他受到了很大启发
in the development of a revolutionary movement
他将自已经历的历史事件
through his history
写就了《震撼世界的十天》
of Ten Days That Shook The World.
《震撼世界的十天》当然是他的杰作
Ten Days That Shook The World was, of course, his masterpiece.
布尔什维克革命的时候他在场
He was there when the Bolshevik Revolution took place.
他是最佳报道者
And his was the best report of it.
麦斯・伊斯曼说约翰・雷德当时…
Max Eastman had this story that John Reed came down,
头发蓬松，在全书关注写着一本书
tousled hair all, you know... And said he was writing a book
十天之内没有人打扰他
and not to disturb him for ten days.
那本书就是《震撼世界的十天》
And that became Ten Days That Shook The World.
估计是这样
Supposedly.
他获得了巨大的成功
He was an enormous, enormous success,
这次成功改变了他的一生
and this success largely changed his whole life, I think,
因为他发现有些东西他能做好
'cause he found out there was something that he could do well,
比任何人都做得好
do practically better than anyone else.
同志们，捕捉社会主义党革命者的计划
"Comrades, we have made a great stride forward in our program
取得了重大的进展
"to capture the Socialist Party for Revolution.
右翼党派的统治已经结束
"The time of right-wing domination of the party has ended.
他们还没来得及 像俄国革命那样炫耀
"They have fallen before the shining example of revolutionary Russia
就像保龄球瓶一样倒下了
"like so many bowling pins!
同志们，我们比预想的还要做得好
"Comrades, we have done better than we could have dreamed.
在社会党执行委员会中
"The left wing has won 12 of the 15 seats
左翼取得15票中的12票胜出
"on the Socialist Party Executive,
包括我自己 埃蒙・麦阿派尼和杰克・雷德
"including myself, Edmund MacAlpine and Jack Reed."
他从此平步青云
He took a tremendous jump forward from there on.
他成了工人阶级革命者
He became a revolutionist on the workers' side,
对威尔逊这样的人 已经不再抱有任何幻想
and he had no more illusions about people like Wilson.
我们都有问题
We all have problems.
你不能逃避问题，是不是？
You can't escape having problems, don't you know?
但要从人性角度考虑这个问题
But to take on the problem of all humanity,
来挽救人性
to save all humanity,
老天，对耶稣而言，那也是天大的事
my God, that was too big even for Jesus Christ.
耶稣就是这样被钉死在十字架上
Don't you know he got himself crucified?
我们要怎么才能做到这些事情？
How the hell do we expect to do those things?
Oh.
路易丝，是你吗？
Louise. Is that you?
你好，哈瑞
Hello, Harry.
最近去哪了？好久不见
Well, where have you been lately? I haven't seen you in a long time.
是的，会议要开一整天吗？
That's right. Is this thing gonna last all day?
可能吧，我们已经被排挤出来了
It might. We've been kicked out.
-被排挤出哪？ -社会党
- Kicked out of what? - The Socialist Party.
-等等，是谁干的？ -那屋子里的每一个人
- Wait, wait. Who got kicked out? - Everybody in that room.
执行委员会把我们赶了出来
The Executive Committee kicked us all out.
-整个左翼？ -对，他们宣布投票无效
- The whole left wing? - That's right. They nullified the election.
-他们能这样做吗？ -已经做了
- Can they do that? - They've done it.
我们占多数，我们有投票权
We're the majority. We have the votes.
但我们却被同僚排挤了出来
We weren't expelled by the membership.
被执行委员踢了出来
We were expelled by the executives.
而你还口口声声叫我们
And you're talking about doing exactly
按照执行委员会的话去做
what the Executive Committee wants us to do.
将党拱手相让！
Give the party back to them without a fight!
对，我们自己组织政党
Yes! And organize our own party!
去你的，路易 社会党本来就是我们自己的党
Goddamn it, Louis, the Socialist Party is our own party!
我们是通过党员投票当权
We were voted into power by its membership
绝不能被执行委员赶走
and we can't be expelled by the executives.
这是非法的举动 如果我们据理而争，我们会赢
It's an illegal act, and if we fight it at the convention, we'll win.
为什么一定要争？
Why do we have to fight?
你这么说什么意思？
What do you mean, "Why do we have to fight?"
大家都是为党尽忠…
For what do we stay in a party
为什么非要争个你死我活？
in which we must win control from the minority, not once, but twice?
什么意思，路易？ 如果有些东西要争取才能得来…
Well, what is it, Louis? You mean, if we must fight for what we deserve,
那就不要争取是吗？ 这就是你的革命思想？
then to hell with it? Is that your idea of revolution?
路易，我想再听听你其他的革命理念
I'd like to hear more about your revolutionary concept, Louis.
我的革命思想 不是我们政党的革命思想
My idea of revolution is not a revolution in my own party!
我们的社会党不是唇枪舌剑的政党
And my idea of a socialist party is not a debating society!
是一个行动的政党！
It is a party of action!
好…
Fine! Fine.
我们能给的最好例子就是召开大会…
The best example we can give them is go to that convention
控制好这个党
and take control of the party!
不，我们自己组织党
No! We form our own party!
我希望相信布尔什维克的在座各位…
And I hope that everybody here who believe in Bolshevism
当晚能来帮助组织一个党
will be there that night to help found that party!
但是你错了
All right, but I say you're wrong,
我会支持社会党的惯例…
and I say that I'm gonna be there at that Socialist Party convention
争取属于自己的席位 我也敦促在座的各位
to take the seat that belongs to me, and I urge everyone here today
不要放弃属于自己的席位
to be there to take the seats that belong to you!
他们好像想脱离群众意义
It's almost like they want to be separated from the masses.
他们想脱离群众，就是这样
They do want to be separated from the masses. That's the point.
我们走
Let's go.
我一直都是少数派
I've been in a minority before.
嗨
Hello.
他之所以喜欢草稿宣言…
While he liked the draft manifesto,
是因为他有点害怕社会爱国者条款
he's a bit nervous about the social-patriot clause.
-打断一下 -按道理说，他要遇到麻烦了
- Excuse me. - Tactically, he's gonna be trouble.
他是要求他的人服从惯例 还是不服从？
Is he gonna bring his people to the convention or not?
这人可以跟你谈上一年的理论
The man will talk theory with you all year.
我不这么想，他会支持佛莱纳
Well, I don't think so. He'll go with Fraina.
不是很好吗？ 他喜欢那宣言，卡诺夫斯基怎么样？
Isn't that nice? He likes the manifesto. How about Carnofsky?
杰克，我们可能得不到 预想的那么多支持
I don't think we're gonna have as much support as we thought, Jack.
我们单刀直入，卡诺夫斯基会怎么说？
We're gonna get in. What did Carnofsky say?
-他持反对意见 -我告诉你，杰克
- Carnofsky said no. - I'm telling you, Jack...
-了解自己的… -一半的佛莱纳支持者会来…
- Just knowing on our own... - Half of Fraina's people would come...
进来！路易丝，你让它安静点行不行？
Come in! Louise, please keep her quiet, will you?
-嗨，埃迪 -怎么…
- Hi, Eddie. - How can...
-嗨，埃迪 -嗨，路易丝，本
- Hello, Eddie. - Hello, Louise, Ben.
嗨
Hey.
埃迪，列文怎么样？
Eddie, what about Levine?
埃迪？
- Eddie? - Yeah.
-列文说了什么？ -他没出现，他…
- What did Levine say? - He never showed. He...
我等了一个多小时
I waited over an hour.
-列文没有露面 -这可不像他的风格
- Levine didn't show. - That doesn't sound like Levine.
对，你们在哪里见面？
Sure it does. Where were you meeting?
在凯西家
In Casey's.
惊讶，真是惊讶
Now, that surprises me. That really surprises me.
我可能没碰着他
I could have missed him.
那边真的很忙
It was really busy in there.
-没碰着他？ -什么意思？
- You could have missed him? - What's that supposed to mean?
我迟到了
I was late.
迟了多久？
How late?
40到45分钟
Forty, forty-five minutes.
诺拉今天早上又开始吐血
Nora started spitting up blood again this morning.
我必须带她去诊所
I had to take her to the clinic,
我还要等我妈妈来接我的孩子
and I had to wait for my mother to come and pick up the kid.
你迟到了45分钟
So you were 45 minutes late.
我以为我能赶到，真的
Yeah. I thought I could make it. I really did.
好吧，我们要联系这人 怎么联系？
All right, we gotta get in touch with the guy. How do we do it?
他现在正在去芝加哥的路上
He's on his way to Chicago.
所以我当时还以为他还在那里
That's one of the reasons I thought he would still be there.
等一下，你以为他还在那里？
Wait a minute, you thought he'd still be there?
-是的 -埃迪，是谁要求见面的？
- Yeah. - Who asked for the meeting, Eddie?
-谁要求见面？ -谁要求见的面？
- Who asked for the meeting? - Who asked for the meeting?
-列文要见面？ -是的，我以为他想见面
- Did Levine want the meeting? - Yeah, I thought he wanted it.
他给我们打过电话吗？
Did he call us?
不，我们给他打的电话
No. We called him.
那他为什么还会等？ 是我们想见面
Then why would he wait? We wanted the meeting.
对不起
I'm sorry.
为何不叫我们当中一个人代替你去？
Well, why didn't you call one of us and get somebody to take your place?
因为我以为我能赶到
Because I thought I could make it.
我以为他会在那里等
I mean, I thought the man would still be there.
你以为…不要自以为是，埃迪
You thought, you thought, you thought. Try not to think too much, Eddie.
同志们指靠你的时候，不要总自以为是
Not when your comrades are depending on you.
要确定
Be sure.
好吧
All right, look.
我们有没办法联系到芝加哥的列文？
Do we have a contact for Levine in Chicago?
给辛格打电话
Let's call Singer.
-你有他的号码？ -可能有
- Do you have a number for him? - Yeah. Well, I've probably got it.
给
Here.
谢谢
Thanks.
别光是喝咖啡…
You know, they might work better
吃点别的东西对你的胃更好
if you put something in your stomach besides coffee.
现在这种情况 你对埃迪是不是太刻薄了？
You're a little hard on Eddie, aren't you, under the circumstances?
你认为我的同情能够帮到 埃迪的妻子？
You think my sympathies can help Eddie's wife?
也许能帮到埃迪
Might help Eddie.
听我说，组建一个政党才能帮助埃迪
Listen to me. Building a party will help Eddie.
4，8，12…
Four, eight, twelve...
我们都有相同的信仰
You know, I think we all believe in the same things.
我们之间
But with us,
或多或少都存在好的意图
it's more or less our good intentions.
和杰克，那是宗教信仰
And with Jack, it's a religion.
我们的老朋友杰克对我们太认真了
Our old friend Jack's getting serious on us.
[1919年，芝加哥]
你好，弗兰克
Okay. Hey, Frank, how are you?
你好
How are you?
请问发生什么事了？
Excuse me. What's happening here?
执行委员会有令，没有红本本不准入内
No one's admitted without a red card. That's the order of the Executive.
我也是执行委员，他也是，他也是…
Well, I'm on the Executive, so is he, so is he...
-没有红本本不准入内 -哪里能弄到红本本？
- No one's admitted without a red card. - Where do we get the red cards?
找资格审查委员会
You'll have to take that up with the Credentials Committee.
资格审查委员会在哪？
And where's the Credentials Committee?
不知道
I don't know.
我看他不希望我们进去
I don't think he wants us to go in there.
与高层人谈话就是难
Well, the way to take the hall is to take the hall.
埃蒙！
Edmund!
埃蒙！杰克！
Edmund! Jack!
好了，我们走，快来，这边
Okay. Let's go. Let's go. Come on, this way!
在提出议程之前，我先宣布…
To propose the agenda, I would like to read a message
资格审查委员会致台下各位的通告
from the Credentials Committee to the floor.
请后边肃静一下好吗？
May we please have order back there?
大厅后边的先生们，请…
In the back of the hall, could we have...
警官，请过去后面看看发生什么事
Sergeant-at-arms, would you see what's going on back there?
女士们先生们，看来有一群擅闯者…
Ladies and gentlemen, it seems we have a group of intruders
试图接管此次会议
who are trying to take over this conference.
我们不会让他们得逞
We're not going to let them.
请坐下，清理通道
Now, please, please sit down. I need these aisles clear.
警官，清理通道
Sergeant-at-arms, I must have these aisles clear!
各位请坐下
Please, everyone, sit down.
这些布尔什维克支持者…
Now, these are Bolshevik sympathizers
试图篡夺党政，我们绝对不容许
who are trying to take over this party, and we're not going to let them.
警察马上就到
The police are coming.
那些人不是社会主义者，而是暴徒
These people aren't socialists. These people are just thugs!
看到了吗？这就是布尔什维克的勾当！
Now you see? That is Bolshevik tactics!
代表们，这些人是冒名顶替者
Come on, delegates. These people are imposters!
他们并不是我们选举出来的领导人
They were not elected to the leadership of this party.
女士们先生们，警察来了
Ladies and gentlemen, the police are coming!
-看到了吗，警官？ -怎么回事？
- You see? The police. - What the hell is this?
执行委员会能够当权的唯一伎俩…
That's the only way the Executive Committee can stay in power,
就是利用资本主义警察
is by the use of the capitalist police.
把红本本拿出来
Flash your red cards!
他们不择手段让工人阶级…
They'll resort to any tactics to keep the working class
远离真正的领导人，因为他们害怕革命
away from its true leadership because they're afraid of revolution!
警官，没有红本本的人不是这里的人
Officers, whoever has no red card does not belong in this room.
举起红本本
Hold up your red cards.
好吧，我们走，不用你们赶
It's all right. We're going. You don't have to throw us out.
如果你们想知道
If you want to know where the true leadership
美国社会党真正领袖在哪里
of the Socialist Party of America is,
五分钟之后在大楼地下室见
it'll be in the basement of this building in five minutes...
-出示红本本 -欢迎你们加入
- Red cards, everybody! ...and you're welcome to join us.
没有红本本的人通通出去
I want anybody who does not have a red card to be out of this hall.
主席同志，我提议 我们该马上组建一个…
Comrade Chairman, I move that we immediately constitute ourselves
真正的共产党
as the bona fide Communist party,
名字叫美国共产主义劳工党
and that we call ourselves the Communist Labor Party of America.
赞成！
I second that motion!
如果我们要组建一个真正的革命党
Well, look, if we're gonna have a really revolutionary party,
那么我们应该向美国工人征求意见
I think what we have to do is to find out from the American worker
然后我们再把信息反馈给他们
what he wants the most and then we have to translate it back to him
通过劳工运动的方式
in terms of the labor movement as a whole.
我们要做的就是让工人想了解更多
What we have to do is make him want more.
让他们迫切要求一场全面革命
We have to make him want the whole goddamn revolution.
楼上的那些人认为卡尔・马克思 只是一个…
Those people upstairs think that Karl Marx was somebody
擅长编写反托拉斯法案的人
who wrote a good antitrust law.
不管我们自己的党叫社会主义劳工党
And whether we call our party the Socialist Labor Party
还是真正社会主义党，不管叫什么
or the Real Socialist Communist... Whatever we call the party,
都不重要，因为…
it doesn't matter because it...
路易，你迷路了吗？
Hello, Lou, are you lost?
没有，我是来告诉朋友们
No. I'm not lost. I'm here to tell my friends
这个新组建的美国共产党
that the newly-formed Communist Party of America
将要在蓝岛大街会见苏联代表
is meeting at the Russian Federation on Blue Island Avenue.
欢迎大家报名参加
We welcome your applications.
新党员将会基于个人成份来判定
They will be judged on an individual basis.
你要判定我们的申请人？
You're gonna judge our applications?
我们要向你申请党员资格？
We're gonna apply to you for membership?
主席同志，我要重申这个问题
Comrade Chairman, I'd like to call that question, please.
前面的提议已经得到通过
The motion has been made and seconded that
我们要立即组建一个真正的共产党
we immediately constitute ourselves as the bona fide Communist party
称之为美国共产主义劳工党
and that we call ourselves the Communist Labor Party of America.
赞成的人请表个态
All those in favor, please signify by saying aye.
赞成！
Aye!
有无人反对？提议通过
Opposed? Motion is carried.
同志们…
Comrades! Comrades!
同志们，内部斗争是个错误
Comrades, this is the wrong time to be fighting against one another.
我们应该联合起来对付资本主义
We should be united in our struggle against the capitalists.
路易，我们6周前就已经考虑过
You should have thought of that six weeks ago, Louis.
如果你的人支持我们，我们早已占大多数
If your people had stayed with us, we'd have had a majority,
我们早就当政
and we'd be in control of that convention upstairs.
我们的成员是你的五倍
We have five times your membership!
路易，你的算法跟你的政策一样愚蠢
Louis, your arithmetic's something like your politics.
我们要去蓝岛大街会见苏联代表
We will be at the Russian Federation on Blue Island Avenue.
希望到时能见到你们
I hope to see some of you there.
主席同志 我建议马上派出代表去莫斯科
Comrade Chairman, I move we immediately send a delegate to Moscow
为美国共产主义劳工党…
to gain recognition by the Comintern
争取国际共产主义的承认
for the Communist Labor Party of America,
-这个代表就是杰克・雷德 -赞同！
- and that delegate be Jack Reed. - Second the motion!
提议通过，同意派遣杰克・雷德…
The motion has been made and seconded to send Jack Reed
作为国际共产主义代表前往莫斯科
to Moscow immediately as the international delegate
为美国共产主义劳工党…
to obtain recognition of the Comintern
争取国际共产主义的承认
for the Communist Labor Party of America.
赞同的请表态
All those in favor, please signify by saying aye.
赞成
Aye!
有无人反对？提议通过
Opposed? Motion is carried.
既然第一条提议…
Since the first question I'm going to be asked...
好了，谢谢
All right, thank you.
同志们 既然共产国际对我的第一个要求…
All right, comrades, since the first question I'm gonna be asked
是关于党员的适合性
by the Comintern is gonna be about membership eligibility,
那么我会很清楚我们的地位…
I think I'm gonna have to be very clear what our position is
与国外语言联盟有重要关系
in relation to the Foreign Language Federation.
我要准确说出我们的要求就是…
I'm gonna have to say exactly what our requirements are
反对任何其他的群体
as opposed to any other group,
我想在我们的党章中 应该明确规定…
and I think we'll have to make it clear on our Platform Committee
在宣言里要说明
and be very clear in the manifesto.
-杰克，祝你莫斯科好运 -好，哈瑞
- Good luck in Moscow, Jack! - Okay, Harry.
你的人认为没有我你同样可以运作报社
Well, I guess you boys think you can run a newspaper without me.
嗨，杰茜
Hello, Jessie.
乖孩子
Good girl.
-嗨 -嗨
- Hello. - Hello.
我跟你直说吧，杰克 我不会跟你去的
Let me make it easy for you, Jack. I'm not going with you.
如果你要去 我不知道我会不会等你回来
And if you go, I'm not sure I'll be here when you get back.
路易丝，共产国际并不认识 埃蒙或者埃弗德…
Louise, you know, the Comintern doesn't know Edmund or Alfred
这些纽约来的北方佬 他们只认识我
from the New York Yankees. They know me.
要去那里的人一定要有背景
Somebody's got to go over there who's got a background.
我们圣诞节就回来
We'd be back by Christmas.
我们不能跟佛莱纳合并
We can't merge with Fraina.
不可能在成员适应性 跟他取得共识
We can't deal with him on membership eligibility.
他不会接受我们一半的党员
He wouldn't accept half of our people.
这人不会干别的事 只会让自己远离那些…
The man is gonna do nothing but alienate himself
潜在的广阔的支援基础
from any potential broad base of support.
他是个社会独立份子
He's sociologically isolated,
从程序上说，他根本处理不了…
programmatically he's impossible to deal with...
你是说他是外国人？
You mean he's a foreigner?
别这样，路易丝
Don't do that, Louise.
六个月前，你们还是朋友
Six months ago, you were friends.
这些人根本就不会说英语
These people can barely speak English.
他们甚至不想融入美国生活
They don't even want to be integrated into American life.
外语联盟也不会在 美国创造布尔什维克语
The Foreign Language Federations aren't gonna create Bolshevism
只不过是照搬俄国人的规矩
in America any more than eating borscht will.
做俄国人，不一定要革命
Being Russian doesn't make a revolution.
你以为美国工人…
Do you think the American workers
会被苏联同盟所领导？
are gonna be led by the Russian federations?
或者像佛莱纳那样的意大利人？
Or an insular Italian like Louis Fraina?
他也不可能在这个国家领导革命
He has no possibility of leading a revolution in this country.
你会有所不同吗？
Unlike you?
我只是说这个国家的革命…
I'm just saying that the revolution in this country
不会被移民者所领导
is not gonna be led by immigrants.
革命？在这个国家？ 什么时候？圣诞之后吗？
Revolution? In this country? When, Jack? Just after Christmas?
就算我们准备好了，你以为我们这次…
Well, what do you think we could've done with the steel strike
钢铁罢工就能成功？
if we'd been ready?
区区3万用理论武装头脑的党员
30,000 party members all armed with a unified theory and program
就能领导36.5万的钢铁工人罢工？
leading 365,000 steelworkers?
关键在于领导
What it takes is leadership.
我们要获得莫斯科那边的认可
And we gotta get it by getting recognition from Moscow.
-我一定要去 -你不一定要去
- I have to go. - You don't have to go.
是你想要去，你想要征服整个世界…
You want to go. You want to go running all over the world ranting and raving
组织高加索人领导革命
and making resolutions and organizing caucuses.
共产党与共产主义劳工党…
What's the difference between the Communist Party
有何区别？
and the Communist Labor Party
除了你跟他各自为政之外 还有区别吗？
except that you're running one and he's running the other?
-我已经答应了 -答应什么？
- I've made a commitment. - To what?
找到四分之一左翼 与二分之一左翼的区别
To the fine distinction between which half of the left of the left
就能让莫斯科认可真正的 美国共产主义劳工党？
is recognized by Moscow as the real Communist Party in America?
无耻的政治家与卑鄙的政治家争论不休
To petty political squabbling between humorless and hack politicians
只是在左翼教条上浪费时间吗？
just wasting their time on left-wing dogma?
获得苏联那边的认可…
To getting the endorsement of a committee in Russia
就能说明共产国际承认下的…
you call the International
你和地下室那14个朋友…
for your group of 14 intellectual friends in the basement
就能让工人对这个国家提出要求？
who are supposed to tell the workers of this country what they want,
就能说明他们要否执政？
whether they want it or not?
写作吧，杰克
Write, Jack.
你不是政治家，你是作家
You're not a politician, you're a writer.
你的写作成就已经超过…
And your writing has done more for the revolution
20年混战的成就，你知道的
than 20 years of this infighting can do, and you know it.
杰克，你是文学家
You're an artist, Jack.
别去
Don't go.
别放弃你的长处
Don't run away from what you do the best.
杰克
Jack.
我会在圣诞节前回来
I'll be back by Christmas.
我要去市里，你什么时候走？
I'm going into the city. When do you leave?
明天
Tomorrow.
-知道了 -我会在圣诞节前回来
- I see. - I'll be back by Christmas.
你会在家吗？
Will you be here?
不知道，见面的时候自然能见到你
I don't know. I'll see you when I see you.
你的护照和证件，你叫詹姆斯・格雷
Here. Your passport and papers. Your name's James Gormley.
快去吧
Go now!
雷德太太，请坐
Well, Mrs. Reed. Sit down.
有什么事吗？
What can I do for you?
你好吗，尤金？
Hello, Gene. How are you?
我很好，你呢？
Fine. And you?
我很好
I'm fine.
坐
Sit down.
-杰克怎么样？ -他很好，他去了俄国
- How's Jack? - He's fine. He's in Russia.
-是吗？ -是的
- Is he? - Yes.
他要为共产主义劳工党…
He's trying to get recognition from the Comintern
争取共产国际的认可
for the Communist Labor Party.
他们的政党已经一分为二
You see, they've split into two different factions.
你呢？又是一个人孤单工作？
And you? Left alone with your work again?
不
No.
事实上是的，但我现在的工作不一样了
Well, actually, yes, but my work is different now.
我到处演讲我在俄国的经历
I do a lot of lecturing about what I saw in Russia.
哦，俄国
Ah, yes, Russia.
俄国对你跟杰克都很好
Russia's been good for you and Jack.
给你理由去约会，给他理由离开家
Given you a way to meet people, given him a reason to leave home.
俄国
Russia.
你是偏激还是在生我气？
Are you really that cynical, or are you angry with me?
我真的很偏激，我干嘛要生你的气？
I'm really that cynical. Why would I be angry with you?
尤金，如果你去过俄国…
Gene, if you'd been to Russia,
那么你对任何事情都不会再偏激
you'd never be cynical about anything again.
你会看到寻常百姓都在转变
You would have seen people transformed. Ordinary people.
路易丝，当一个美国人的智慧双眼 闪闪发亮时我会很紧张
Louise, something in me tightens when an American intellectual's eyes shine
尤其是他们吹捧俄国人的时候
and they start to talk to me about the Russian people.
-等等… -我会说留意了
- Wait... - Something in me says, "Watch it.
一个新版的爱尔兰天主教 已经提供给你新的信仰
"A new version of Irish Catholicism is being offered for your faith."
-不是的 -我就是不清楚…
- It's not like that. - And I wonder why
为什么见惯世面的路易丝・雷德…
a lovely wife like Louise Reed who's just seen the brave new world
会和我这么一个偏激狂坐在一起
is sitting around with a cynical bastard like me
而不是跟随理想主义的老公 在俄国驰骋疆场？
instead of trotting all over Russia with her idealistic husband.
这样的转变是值得的
It's almost worth being converted.
我来错地方了
Well, I was wrong to come.
你和杰克因为激进而拥有许多 中产阶级的梦想
You and Jack have a lot of middle-class dreams for two radicals.
杰克的梦想是能够领导美国工人
Jack dreams that he can hustle the American working man,
而工人的梦想是不劳而获，坐享其成
whose one dream is to be rich enough not to have to work,
所以才加入了他所领导的政党
into a revolution led by his party.
你的梦想就是 在你跟某个男人上床之前…
And you dream that if you discuss the revolution with a man
如果你跟他讨论革命
before you go to bed with him,
那么你是在传教而非在做爱
it'll be missionary work rather than sex.
看到你跟你杰克这么认真对待 你的运动我深感难过
I'm sorry to see you and Jack so serious about your sports.
也对你感到失望，路易丝
It's particularly disappointing in you, Louise.
一享受到自由恋爱时，你就欲火焚身
You had a lighter touch when you were touting free love.
看不出来你已经成评论家了，尤金
Boy, you've become quite the critic, haven't you, Gene?
背靠椅子就能分析透彻我们
Just leaned back and analyzed us all.
被灌输自由恋爱思想的女人结了婚
Duplicitous women who tout free love and then get married,
盲从的记者加入了革命…
power-mad journalists who join the revolution
而不是袖手旁观
instead of observing it,
中产阶级激进分子来寻欢作乐…
middle-class radicals who come looking for sex
顺便谈谈俄国革命
and then talk about Russia.
你这样的人真可悲
It must seem so contemptible to a man like you
竟然还有勇气端坐在这里…
who has the courage to sit on his ass and observe human inadequacy
坐视人性的缺陷
from the inside of a bottle.
但我从未见你帮过任何人
Well, I've never seen you do anything for anyone.
也从未见你给别人任何东西
I've never seen you give anything to anyone,
所以我能理解你会怀疑 别人动机不良
so I can understand why you might suspect the motives of those who have.
不管杰克的动机是什么…
But whatever Jack's motives are, how...
我似乎触及到了你的伤口
I seem to have touched a wound.
你是个受伤的王八蛋
You're a wounding son of a bitch,
不管我给你带来什么伤害 你已经让我付出了代价
and whatever I've done to you, you've made me pay for it.
路易丝
Louise.
杰茜！
Jessie!
嗨，杰茜，快回来
Hey, Jess, come on! Come here, Jess.
杰茜，回来
Jessie, come here.
杰茜
Jessie.
杰茜？
Jessie?
晚上好
- Oh! - Good evening.
经美国司法部长授权…
By the order of the Attorney General of the United States,
米切尔・帕默探长奉命前来搜查
A. Mitchell Palmer, I have a warrant here
并逮捕约翰・雷德
for the arrest of one John Silas Reed.
弗兰克，上楼看看
Look upstairs, Frank.
-以什么罪名逮捕？ -煽动暴乱
- Arrest for what? - Sedition.
-他在哪里？ -什么煽动暴乱？
- Where is he? - What do you mean by sedition?
女士，别问我，问伍德洛・威尔逊
Lady, don't ask me. Ask Woodrow Wilson.
告诉我他在哪里
Just tell me where he is.
我看你不像是什么…
I don't suppose there's a chance
布尔什维克煽动家，是不是？
of you being a Bolshevik agitator, is there?
你干嘛不找找看 有什么煽动你的东西？
Why don't you just look around, and see how agitated you get?
在1919年
In 1919,
只有不到…
there were no more
四五个美国人…
than four or five Americans
进入到苏联
who got into Russia
因为整个国家周边都被包围着
because the country was surrounded on all sides.
当时有禁令，所以我们只能非法偷渡
You were actually forbidden to go, and you could only go illegally.
穿过芬兰是非常危险的
It was very dangerous to go through Finland.
因为芬兰是白色政权统治
Because the Finns were a White government,
那里反对红色政权
and they were bitterly opposed to the Reds.
他们决定将…
They decided to strangle
布尔什维克扼杀在摇篮之中
the revolutionary Bolshevik infant in its cradle.
16支部队从东西两路进逼苏联…
And 16 armies went into Russia from the east and from the west,
为了消灭布尔什维克势力…
for the purpose of wiping out the Bolsheviks
以及镇压革命
and wiping out the revolution
让基督教文明恢复到公正的地位
and restoring Christian civilization to its rightful place.
说英语吧
Speak English.
吃柠檬吧，很难吃得到的
Have a lemon. You won't see one for a long time.
谢谢，我只想知道你是否觉得…
Thank you. I just want to know if you think that I was clear
-我刚才说的已然清楚… -非常清楚
- in what I said about... - Eminently clear.
加盐吗？
Salt?
-加盐？ -用来配柠檬
- Salt? - For the lemon.
谢谢
Thank you.
我看见你吃柠檬皮
I see you eat the peel with the lemon.
抵抗坏血病，洋葱也行
Fights the scurvy. So does the onion.
一起吃抵抗力更强
Together, they fight better.
我真正想知道的是…
You see, what I really wanted to do
您能不能坦率地回答…
was ask your frank opinion whether we...
我们党是否会得到委员会的认可
You think we'll get the endorsement from the committee.
-当然是非正式的问 -非正式？
- I ask unofficially, of course. - Unofficially?
非正式地，我不知道
Unofficially, I don't know.
这是一个…
Yeah, well, it's such a...
美国式的问题，我…
It's a peculiarly American problem and I...
-我说得够清楚吗？ -非常清楚
- You do think I was clear? - Quite clear.
但你的提议不一定能保证得到认可
In this case, however, clarity does not necessarily guarantee endorsement.
我不知道，也许会如此
Well, I don't know. In this case, I think perhaps it might.
实际上，我不…
You know, in fact, I don't...
我其实是想做一个详细的报告
What I really want to do is to make a detailed report
让执行委员会了解美国的情况
for the Executive Committee to read on conditions in America.
我想把美国劳工联合会的整个历史…
You see, I'd like to deal in that report with the entire history
写在报告里面
of the American Federation of Labor.
我想写明它支持革命战争的立场
I'd like to deal with its support of the war, you see.
我要检举世界产业工人组织的迫害
And I'm gonna talk about the persecution of the IWW,
还要反映爱国社团的崛起
I'm gonna deal with the rise of the patrioteering societies,
以及举报社会党领导人的叛变
and the capitulation of leading socialists.
-我要…我说得太快了吗？ -不，继续说
- I'm gonna... Am I speaking too quickly? - No, no. Go on.
我要反映美国劳工崛起的战斗性
And so I will deal with the rising militancy of American labor.
还有西雅图和温尼伯湖的罢工
I'll talk about the general strikes in Seattle and Winnipeg,
以及波士顿警察罢工
the Boston police strike.
我要讨论普拉姆计划 以及左派的特殊态度和政策
I'm gonna discuss the Plumb Plan, and particularly the attitude
世界产业工人组织对他们的影响
and the policies of the AF of L and IWW toward them.
之后，我想重要的是…
Now, after that, I think it's important...
雷德同志，共产国际执行委员会…
Comrade Reed, the Executive Committee of the Comintern
决定对共产主义工党和美国共产党…
has decided against endorsing either the Communist Labor Party
不予承认
or the Communist Party of America,
随即命令两个政党马上合并
and instructs the two parties to merge forthwith.
这里坐，雷德同志
Sit here, Comrade Reed.
你的座位之所以被占用…
This time, your usual chair, as you can see,
是因为我们现在要详细研究美国的形势
is now occupied by your detailed report on American conditions.
一个非常深入的研究，非常清晰
A most penetrating study. Very, very clear.
谢谢
Thank you.
显然，还不够清楚
Obviously, it wasn't clear enough.
拉德克同志
Comrade Radek,
我想，你们肯定搞错了…
I think there must have been some mistake
我回美国的旅程安排
about my travel arrangements about my return to the United States.
我好像还要去宣传部那里报到
Well, it seems as if I've been asked to report to the Propaganda Bureau.
没错
That is right.
雷德同志，执行委员会决定…
Comrade Reed, the Executive Committee has decided
宣传部非常需要你
you are very much needed at the Propaganda Bureau.
我们要你留在苏联工作，直到7月
We plan for you to remain in Soviet Russia until July.
宣传部非常欢迎你的到来
You're very welcome to the Bureau of Propaganda.
非常感谢
Well, thank you very much,
可是我的旅程已经安排好了
but I thought that these travel arrangements had been made.
我要去拉脱维亚或者芬兰边境
I have to get to the Latvian or the Finnish border.
你建议去哪个边境，雷德同志？
And to which border would you suggest, Comrade Reed?
我明白火车旅行此刻很危险
Well, I understand that train travel is very dangerous at the moment...
他为何要坐火车？
Why does he need a train?
因为我有很紧急的私人事项…
Because I have urgent personal considerations and responsibilities
-要回美国… -什么事项呢？
- in the United States and I... - Of what nature?
-你说什么？ -什么要事呢？
- Excuse me? - Of what nature?
-我有家庭 -我们大家都有家庭
- I have a family. - We all have families.
我只能代表我自己说话 我要见我的妻子
Well, I can speak only for myself and I must see my wife.
这非常紧急
It's very urgent,
我只需要火车上一个座位
and I ask only for a single place on a train.
可你已经有座位了
But you have a place on the train!
你在这革命的火车上有座位了
You have a place on the train of this revolution.
你和其他革命者一样，都是最优秀的
You have been like so many others, the best revolutionaries.
你是这火车机车上的一个工程师
One of the engineers on the locomotive of this train
要让革命在党的领导下 顺着历史的轨迹…
that pulls this revolution on the tracks of historical necessity
全速前进
laid out for it by the party.
你现在不能离开，我们找不到人替代你
You can't leave us now. We can't replace you.
-你有什么权利离开… -我不确定
- What right do you have you to leave... - I'm not sure.
做什么？去见你的妻子？
To do what? To see your wife?
去年在国际议会上…
Last year at the International Congress
我得知我的儿子得了斑疹伤寒症…
I learned that my son was very ill of typhus.
我都没去看我的儿子
I didn't go to see my son
因为我知道政党需要我
because I knew I was needed where I was placed by the party.
你不明白的是…
What you don't understand is...
你想放弃这个重要时刻吗？
Would you like to abandon this moment in your life?
你还会得到这个时刻吗？
Would you ever get this moment again?
-我不会放弃革命！ -雷德同志，你是一名作家
- I am not abandoning the revolution! - Comrade Reed, you're a writer.
人们知道和尊重你的工作
People know and respect your work.
-你说话很有权威 -兹诺维耶同志
- You speak with authority of feeling. - Comrade Zinoviev,
在过去的八个星期…
for the past eight weeks,
我完全不能和我妻子取得联系
I've been completely unable to communicate with my wife
或者和我在美国的朋友联系
or with my comrades in the United States.
我要回去，我想要你的帮助
I need to go back. I would like your help.
雷德同志，你可以回去做你的私事
Comrade Reed, you can always go back to your private responsibilities,
我也可以
so can I.
但你永远不会有这次历史性的机会了
You can never, never come back to this moment in history.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我无权牵扯到你的私生活
I have no right to tell you about your own life.
你比我更清楚
You know it better than I do.
逃离苏联可以说是难上加难
Maybe it was impossible to get out of Russia.
到处都是白军
There was White armies all around,
要成功逃亡简直就像做梦
so escape was not dreamt of.
我们接到杰克的消息
We had a communication from Jack.
他在芬兰的监狱里，不能自由通话
He was in prison in Finland where he couldn't communicate freely.
但他传话给我…
But he got word out to me
让我捎口信给路易丝
to take a message to Louise.
我记得去到路易丝家，她就住在我附近
And I remember walking over to Louise, she lived right near me.
我去到路易丝在帕特森的公寓
I walked over to Louise's apartment on Patson Place,
跟她谈了一个晚上杰克的事
and spent an evening with her talking about Jack,
她对杰克被困的消息非常激动
and she talked very earnestly about Jack's plight.
雷德夫人，美国政府无权干涉…
Mrs. Reed, the United States cannot involve itself
芬兰的内部事务
in the internal affairs of Finland.
难道美国领事…
Are you trying to tell me the American Consul
-不能给出任何消息？ -恐怕不能
- can't give you any information? - I'm afraid that there's nothing
-国务院对此无能为力 -别跟我说废话
- that the State Department can do. - Don't give me that garbage.
如果他的名字是洛克菲勒 那情况就会大不相同
If his name were Rockefeller, there'd be something you could do.
雷德夫人 如果你丈夫的名字是洛克菲勒
Mrs. Reed, if your husband's name were Rockefeller,
那他都不会背负上…
I think he would hardly be under indictment
阴谋推翻美国政府的罪名
for a conspiracy to overthrow the United States Government.
他只有一个肾脏，他会病重的
He has only one kidney. He could be dangerously ill.
那是你丈夫自己冒的险，雷德夫人
That is a chance that your husband took, Mrs. Reed,
他离开美国时，都没有签证或者护照
when he left the United States without an exit visa or a passport.
再见，雷德夫人
Good day, Mrs. Reed.
美国和联盟国都参加了…
The United States participated with the Allies
反对苏联的军事行动
in military expeditions against the Soviet Union
试图战胜他们，侵略他们
in an attempt to overcome them, invade them,
建立另一个政府
and set up another government. Oh, yes. Yes.
有这么一个陷阱…
There was a noose
设在苏联周围
to be pulled around Russia
让你知道整个国家…
which gave you an idea of how a whole country
会陷入四面楚歌的境地
can be surrounded east, west, south, and north.
你的名字，以及芬兰联络员的名字
Your name, and the name of your contact in Finland.
我不知道是什么颜色
I don't know what color...
我自己拿吧
I'll just get it myself.
-你会得到… -你要我们现在做吗？
- Would you get some... - Would you like us to do it now?
-好 -好的
- Okay. - Oh, okay.
-好了 -我明白
- All right. - I understand.
从上面？
From the top?
知道，然后他们画了一幅地图
Oh, I see. Then they made a map.
泰瑞跟我谈过了
Terry spoke to me.
路易丝，你根本不知道这次旅行 对一个女人来说有多困难
Louise, I don't think you realize how difficult this trip to be for a woman.
你必须偷渡出去
You'd have to stow away.
就算你到了那里，也需要六个月…
If you got there at all, it would take you six months to...
泰瑞说你能给我安排一条货船
Terry said that he thought that you could arrange a freighter for me
-一直到挪威 -不知道你为什么这样说
- as far as Norway. - Don't know why you're saying it.
你知道我的意思吗？
You know what I mean?
坐下
Sit down.
我想跟你谈一些事
I want to talk to you about something.
…说明地图
...indicates the map.
我可以去
I could go.
我能以海员的身份去，不需要审查
I can sign on as a seaman. There'd be no questions asked.
在这种情况下…
I think under the circumstances...
别这样看我 杰克・雷德也算是我的朋友
Don't look at me like that. Jack Reed's a friend of mine.
我不会让那王八蛋死在监狱里的
I'm not gonna let the son of a bitch rot in jail.
只是好像我没兴趣…
Just seemed to me that I'm not as interested...
这样的话…
...and at this point...
好了
Okay.
他不是要来找我谈这事吗？
Wasn't he supposed to come over to me on this?
我明早就跟泰瑞谈
I'll talk to Terry in the morning.
在那里放个十字架
Where the cross is made...
希望那些王八蛋能合作
I wish these son-of-a-bitches could act.
约翰雷德:正尝试所有解决办法
停止活动，坚持住 爱你的路易丝
你的血压非常高
Your blood pressure is very high.
他们只给我吃咸鱼
They only give me some kind of salted fish.
你嘴巴里的血是从牙龈里出来的
The blood in your mouth is from the gums.
你得了坏血症
You have scurvy.
深刻的红印，同志
An impressive shade of red, comrade.
可以帮我发电报给我妻子吗？
Could you send a cable to my wife?
雷德先生，我有东西给你
Mr. Reed, I have something for you.
-有电报吗？ -还没有
- Is there a cable? - There's nothing yet.
你要用温水服这些药粉 每天一次
You should take one of these powders in a glass of water, once a day.
她有消息捎给我吗？
Has she sent word to me here?
他们不会说的 我们的人什么都找不到
They won't say. Our people can find out nothing.
你被释放了
You are being released.
我要告诉你 我完全忘记了约翰・雷德
You know, I must tell you, I lost sight of John Reed completely.
但我听说…
But what I heard was
布尔什维克通过收买几个芬兰教授…
the Bolsheviki traded some Finnish professors
[1920年，彼得格勒] 来释放约翰・雷德
for the release of John Reed.
约翰・雷德
John Reed.
我们是来欢迎你的
We are here to welcome you.
能带我去电报局吗？
Could you take me to the telegraph office?
-好的，上车吧 -谢谢
- Yes. Get in. - Thank you.
路易丝・拜伦，克洛顿…
"Louise Bryant, Croton-on..."
哈森
Hudson.
哈森…纽约…美国
"...Hudson, New York, USA.
“我很安全，句号”
"I'm safe. Stop."
“请联系…”
"Please contact..."
“联系，请联系…”
Contact. Please contact.
“联系彼得格勒电报局，句号”
"Contact Petrograd telegraph office. Stop.
“没收到你的消息，句号”
"Have received no word from you. Stop.
“请原谅…”
"Please for... Forgive..."
“请原谅圣诞节的事”
Please forgive Christmas.
“请原谅圣诞节的事，句号 爱你的杰克”
"Please forgive Christmas. Stop. Love, Jack."
可以马上发送吗？
Could you send that right away?
列宁同志说…
Comrade Lenin said
他会为约翰・雷德收买50位教授
he would trade, for John Reed, fifty professors.
路易丝・拜伦，克洛顿-哈森
"Louise Bryant, Croton-on-Hudson,
纽约，美国
"New York, USA."
-美国 -“美国，立刻…”
- USA. - "USA. Immediate."
-“速回…” -“速回…”
- Immediate return... - "Immediate return..."
-“美国…” -“美国…”
- ... United States... - "...United States..."
-“不可能” -“不可能”
- ... impossible. - "...impossible."
-路易丝・拜伦，克洛顿… -克洛顿
- Louise Bryant, Croton... - Croton.
-克洛顿… -克洛顿-哈森
- "Croton-on..." - Croton-on-Hudson.
克洛顿-哈森，纽约，美国
"Croton-on-Hudson, New York, USA.
“还没收到你的消息，句号 没有固定的地址，句号”
"Still no word from you. Stop. Have no fixed address. Stop."
路易丝・拜伦，克洛顿-哈森，美国纽约
"Louise Bryant. Croton-on-Hudson, New York, USA.
“要知道，你还好吗？句号”
"Must know, are you well? Stop."
-“不…” -“不明白…”
- "Do not..." - Do not understand.
“不明白为何没有你的消息，句号”
"Do not understand why no word from you. Stop."
路易丝・拜伦，克洛顿-哈森，美国纽约
"Louise Bryant. Croton-on-Hudson, New York, USA.
-“需要…” -“需要消息”
- "Need..." - Need word.
“需要你的消息，句号 不明白你为何沉默，句号”
"Need word from you. Stop. Do not understand your silence. Stop"
路易丝・拜伦，克洛顿-哈森
"Louise Bryant. Croton-on-Hudson,
-美国纽约 -你查了“里德”吗？
- "New York, USA." - Did you check R-E-A-D?
是的
Yes. Yes.
也查了“莱德”吗？
And you checked R-E-l-D also?
我查过了“莱德”
I have looked R-E-l-D,
“里德”
R-E-A-D,
“瑞德”，我查过高曼和拜伦
R-E-D. I have looked Goldman and Bryant.
我只是…对不起，请等一下
I'm just... Excuse me. One second.
如果…
Lf, if...
我想可能有一些字拼错了
I thought maybe there's some other way of misspelling the name.
-也查了“莱德”吗？ -是的，雷德同志
- You also looked under R-E-l-D? - Yes, Comrade Reed.
-你还想怎么样？ -很多人在等
- Yes, yes. What do you want? - There's many people wait.
-对不起 -有消息，我们会通知你
- Excuse me. - Lf something come, we'll notify you.
你听到什么？
What have you heard?
没什么，你呢？
Not much. What have you heard?
我没听见，我在等 他们监禁了更多无政府主义者
I don't hear. I wait. They've jailed more anarchists.
但他们让比尔・莎托夫 做西伯利亚铁路的领导
But they made Bill Shatoff head of the Siberian railway.
他们对我很好 我保存着自己的判断力
They treated me very well, and I'm reserving my judgment.
-聪明 -有很多事情我不明白
- Well, that's wise. - There's so much I don't understand.
森林离彼得格勒很近
There are forests within easy reach of Petrograd.
城市为什么还这么冷？
Why is this city freezing?
我问了兹诺维耶
I asked Zinoviev.
他说敌人破坏了所有运输通道
He said our enemies have destroyed all the means of transportation
杀光了我们的马，还有我们的人
and killed off our horses as well as our men.
我们怎么运输？
How would we get at it?
我说，彼得格勒的人呢？
I said, "What about the people of Petrograd?
他们可以一起走路去 用绳子把木头拖回来
"They could go there together on foot and haul the wood back with ropes."
他说“是的，那会让人更暖和”
He said, "Oh, yes, it would make the people warmer,
“但会耽误政策的施行”
"but it would interfere with the carrying out of the main political policy."
-你收到美国埃玛的来信？ -是的
- You get letters from America, E. G? - Oh, yes.
全都被司法局拆开 希望他们喜欢看，我可不喜欢
All opened by the Justice Department. I hope they enjoy what they read. I don't.
所以我问他“政策是什么？”
So I asked him, "What are the main political policies?"
他说“集中无产阶级先锋派…”
He said, "Concentration of all power in the hands
“手中的所有权力”
"of the proletarian avant-garde.
“革命先锋派是共产党”
"The avant-garde of the revolution, which is the Communist Party."
有人提到路易丝吗？
Anybody mention Louise?
没有，你没有她的消息吗？
I don't think so. You haven't heard from her?
我给她发了电报，但没有回复
I've sent her cables, but I don't get any answer.
-多久了？ -很久了
- For how long? - A long time.
等等
Wait.
莱斯・威廉姆斯在信中提到她
Rhys Williams mentioned her in his letter.
他也没收到她的消息
He hasn't heard from her, either.
他怎么说的？
What'd he say?
他说他想联系她
I think he said that he'd tried to reach her
在圣诞节后，但她离开纽约了
sometime after Christmas, but she'd left New York.
多久前的事？
How long ago was that?
信怎么也要花两个月才到这里
Well, you know how these letters take a couple of months to get here.
等到我看到时 寄信的人要么坐牢，要么被驱逐
By the time I get them, whoever sent it is either in jail or deported.
-就是那样 -是哪封？
- That's it. - Which?
-那封 -莱斯・威廉姆斯
- There. - Rhys Williams.
Oh.
-要三思而后行 -是的
- First the eyes go, then the legs. - Yeah.
我也不清楚燃料的情况
Yeah, I don't understand the fuel situation, either.
我不知道…
I don't know...
他说她离开了城市
He says she seems to be out of town.
他只那样说？
That's all he said?
是的
Yeah.
他说了奥尼尔什么？
What did he say about O'Neill?
奥尼尔？没说什么
O'Neill? Nothing.
拜托，他说了什么？
Come on, what did he say?
没什么
Nothing.
可以看看吗？
Can I see it?
对不起
I'm sorry.
我只是不知道她去了哪…
I just don't know where...
杰克，坐吧
Jack, sit down.
如果路易丝来这里
If Louise were to come here,
她就要非法偷渡出国
she'd have to leave the United States illegally,
然后和你过流亡的生活 再也回不了家
then live in exile with you, and never go home again.
这一切都是为了不属于她的革命
All for the sake of a revolution she was never any part of.
她为什么要那样做？
Why should she?
是你选择了革命的生活道路
You chose the life of a revolutionary.
她没有
She didn't.
你的电报只会让司法部监视她
Your cables only focus the Justice Department's attention on her,
对她最不利的就是…
and the most seditious thing they can accuse her of
她是你的妻子
is being your wife.
放过她吧
Leave her alone.
让她选择自己的未来
Let her choose her own future.
但她为什么不回电报？
Why hasn't she answered me?
我想这也算是一种回复
I think she has answered you.
他被释放了，没说他在哪里
He's been released. They won't tell me where he is.
你知道，她很讨厌…
Do you know, she was much hated
衣服的奢华
for her extravagance in clothes.
很久以前，有人跟我说…
Well, a long time ago, somebody said to me,
那些…
"People who...
那些处于危险中的女人
"Women whose lives have been in danger
在很长时期都总是很奢侈
"over a long period are always the most extravagant."
同志们，和许多被误导的政策一样
Comrades, as wrong-headed as many of its policies are,
世界产业工人组织是革命的联盟
the IWW is a revolutionary union
而美国劳工联合会不是
and the American Federation of Labor is not.
想打入美国劳工联合会内部…
To think we can infiltrate the American Federation of Labor
将它转变成革命联合是没有希望的
and convert it to revolutionary policies is hopeless.
翻译
Translation.
同志们，错误翻译
Comrades, that's the wrong translation.
他不是那样说的
That's not what he said.
他在说什么？
What's he saying?
为了能和大会与会者达成一致
For us to make a point on the floor of the Congress,
我们必须…
we have to go
从英语转译为德语
from our own English language into the official German language
再到意大利语 或者西班牙语，或者法语
to the Italian, or Spanish, or French language.
-当反应… -你有什么问题？
- And then, when the response from... - What is your question, please?
为了工会的事宜…
Simply for the labor union issue,
我们能让英语成为大会的…
could we have the English language as an official language
官方语言吗？
on the floor of the Congress?
雷德同志，你已经第三次提这个建议了
Comrade Reed, this is the third time you have raised this proposal!
这个问题早已有了结果
The issue has been decided.
我们必须推进到国家和殖民的事宜
We must move on to the national and colonial issues!
美国真正的工人革命者
Real revolutionary workers in the United States
很久前就放弃了工会联盟…
quit the AF of L a long time ago
然后加入了世界产业工人组织
and joined the IWW.
我们要让苏联人明白这一点
We have to make the Russians understand this,
所以我们需要你们的支持
and that's why we want your support
延长会议，让辩论公开化
to extend the session of congress and to keep the debate open.
杰克，你没事吧？
Jack, are you okay?
-你跟萨多谈过吗？ -谈过
- Did you talk to Sadoul? - Yes, I did.
同志们，我仍然反对结束讨论
Comrades, I'm still opposed to closing the discussion here.
我想之所以讨论结束…
I think that this discussion is being closed
是为了避免听到美英代表团的心声
to avoid hearing the American and the British delegations.
如果不是出于这个原因的话
And if for no other reason than that,
那么讨论就应该继续
it shows that discussion should continue.
拉德克同志用这个评论…
Comrade Radek uses this sort of remark
代替争论，结果他想不了了之
in place of an argument and as a result, he doesn't want to talk about it.
雷德是不怕区别歪曲的事实的
What Reed says is not distinguished by excessive fear of distorting the truth.
他日夜都在努力，声称…
He goes on day and night and has the cheek to claim
讨论被人为中断
that the discussion is being broken off
因为有些人害怕伟大的约翰・雷德
because of fear of the great might of John Reed.
雷德同志 你这样谈到明天早上都完不了
Comrade Reed, you may have time to discuss it until tomorrow morning.
别人没有这个时间
Other people do not have the time.
拉德克同志，没时间讨论这事的人
Comrade Radek, other people that don't have the time for this discussion
是世界产业工人组织的101个领导
are 101 leaders of the IWW
而今他们正在美国的监狱坐牢
who are in jail today in the United States
仅仅因为他们持有革命观点
because of their revolutionary views.
如果我们出卖这些同志…
And if we turn our back on these comrades
不能带领激进的美国劳工联合会…
out of some pipe dream to radicalize the American Federation of Labor
忘记这个白日梦，那就是羞耻
which cannot be done, it is a disgrace.
我们在本届六次会议上 讨论过这个问题
We've discussed this during six sessions of this commission.
今天一天都在讨论这个问题
We spent whole day today discussing it,
而你竟然说是我们 想停止讨论这个问题？
and you insinuate we are trying to dismiss the issue?
我们还没讨论充分
We haven't had enough discussion...
我们没有为我的朋友讨论充分
We haven't had enough discussion for my friend here
路易斯・佛莱纳和我在这个问题上 想法一致
to realize that Louis Fraina and I think alike on this problem.
我们代表团的每个美国人
Every American on our delegation,
-英国代表团的每个人… -你是这个委员会的一员
- every man on the English delegation... - You are a member of this committee.
你不是独立的政党代表
You are not an independent political party.
兹诺维耶同志 我不会被这个委员会所压制
Comrade Zinoviev, I will not be steamrollered by this committee
在这个问题上 我们还没有一个正确的认识
that has not had a proper education on this problem.
实际上…
On the fact...
讨论结束了
The discussion is closed.
如果雷德同志希望作陈述
However, if Comrade Reed wishes to make a statement,
他有两分钟的时间
he will have two minutes to do so.
我谨代表美国代表团在此声明…
I would merely want to say that on behalf of the American delegates,
我方拒绝在此事上投票
that we will refuse to vote on these theses,
我本人辞去在委员会的职位
and that I myself will resign my seat on this committee.
杰克，我想我们必须面对…
Jack, I think we have to face it.
我们的梦在苏联破灭了
The dream that we had is dying in Russia.
如果布尔什维克意味着 农民占领土地
If Bolshevism means the peasants taking the land,
工人占领工厂
the workers taking the factories,
那苏联就不是布尔什维克的天下了
Russia's one place where there's no Bolshevism.
我可以和警察争，可以和将军打
You know, I can argue with cops, I can fight with generals.
就是不能和官僚主义者斗
I can't deal with a bureaucrat.
你觉得兹诺维耶 不比官僚主义者坏吗？
You think Zinoviev is nothing worse than a bureaucrat?
苏联人不再有地方自治权了
The Soviets have no more local autonomy.
都成了中央集权
The central state has all the power.
所有的权利掌握在少数人手里
All the power is in the hands of a few men
他们在破坏革命
and they are destroying the revolution.
他们在破坏苏联共产主义的希望
They are destroying any hope of real Communism in Russia.
他们在把像我这样的人关进监狱
They're putting people like me in jail.
我对革命的理解是…
My understanding of revolution
它不是对政治异己的连续消灭
is not a continual extermination of political dissenters,
我不想参与其中
and I want no part of it.
每个报社要么关门大吉
Every single newspaper's been shut down
要么被政党控制
or taken over by the party.
任何一个被怀疑是反革命的人…
Anyone even vaguely suspected of being a counter-revolutionary
都有可能被就地正法 这何时才是个头？
can be taken out and shot without a trial. Where does that end?
以防御为名义
Is any nightmare justifiable
就有理由掀起反对反革命的恶梦？
in the name of defense against counter-revolution?
梦会在苏联破灭，但我不会
The dream may be dying in Russia, but I'm not.
或许过一段时间，我要逃离这里
It may take some time. I'm getting out.
好像你对运动中的革命感到很迷惑
You sound like you're a little confused by the revolution in action, E.G.
直到现在，你只在理论上说
Up to now, you've only dealt with it in theory.
你觉得事情会怎样？
What did you think this thing was gonna be?
难道是舆论的革命
A revolution by consensus
大家围坐一起 喝着咖啡侃侃而谈吗？
where we all sat down and agreed over a cup of coffee?
什么都没用
Nothing works.
去年死了四百万人
Four million people died last year.
不是死于打仗
Not from fighting a war,
而是死于饥荒和斑疹伤寒症 军国极权的国家…
they died from starvation and typhus in a militaristic police state
镇压了自由和人权
that suppresses freedom and human rights
什么都没用
where nothing works.
死人是因为法国，英国和美国的封锁
They died because of a French, British and American blockade
所有食物和药物的供应被切断
that cut off all food and medical supplies
因为反革命分子破坏工厂
and because counter-revolutionaries have sabotaged the factories
铁路和电话，因为那些…
and the railroads and the telephones, and because the people,
贫穷无知迷信文盲的人
the poor, ignorant, superstitious, illiterate people,
想自己做主主持大局，就像你说的那样做
are trying to run things themselves, just as you always said that they should,
但他们不知道怎么主持大局
but they don't know how to run them yet.
你真的觉得日子会立刻好起来吗？
Did you really think things would work right away?
你真的期望社会改革…
Did you really expect social transformation
和谋杀过程一样快速吗？
to be anything other than a murderous process?
这是战争，埃玛 我们必须把它看作战争去打
It's a war, E.G., and we gotta fight it like we fight a war,
有纪律，有恐惧，有战火
with discipline, with terror, with firing squads,
否则我们就放弃算了
or we just give it up.
四百万人不是死于战争
Those four million people didn't die fighting a war.
他们死于一个无法起效的制度！
They died from a system that cannot work!
这才刚开始，埃玛
It's just the beginning, E.G.
不会跟我们想象的那样可怕
It's not happening the way we thought it would.
不会跟我们想象的那样发生
It's not happening the way we wanted it to,
但肯定会发生
but it's happening.
如果你现在放弃…
If you walk out on it now,
那么你的生命还有什么意义？
what's your whole life meant?
我的辞职申请书批了吗？
Could you tell me if my resignation is ready for signature yet?
-批了 -很好
- It is. - Good.
可以看看吗？
May I see it?
谢谢
Thank you.
-谢谢，雷德同志 -欢迎回来，雷德同志
- Thank you, Comrade Reed. - Welcome back, Comrade Reed.
现在你可以代表美国工人…
Now you'll be able to represent the American workers
在即将举行的巴库会议上
at the forthcoming congress at Baku
鼓励中东人发起革命
to inspire revolution among the peoples of the Middle East.
准备迎接艰难的旅行吧
Prepare for a difficult trip.
我们唯一的路线是 穿越分隔的领土
Our only route is through divided territory.
一些知识分子散布谣言…
Some of these intellectuals spread rumors
说他改变了主意
that he changed his mind afterwards,
企图改变主意…
trying to, you know,
证明他醒悟了
show that he came to his senses.
那是荒谬的
It's preposterous.
这些人，我都不记得了
These men, well, I don't even remember them.
我也不想记住他们
I don't want to remember them.
所有通往巴库的列车都已取消
All trains to Baku canceled because of attacks
因为受到了反革命分子的袭击
by counter-revolutionaries.
肯定有去巴库的列车
There must be some train to Baku.
所有通往巴库的列车取消
All trains to Baku canceled
因为受到反革命分子的袭击
because of attacks by counter-revolutionaries.
肯定有去巴库的车
There has to be something to Baku.
路易丝？
Louise?
埃玛？
Emma?
埃玛
Emma.
你是怎么到苏联的？
How in the name of God did you get into Russia?
-我不知道要多久 -你要等一会儿
- I had no idea how long it would take. - So, you'll wait for a while.
没准你刚到那里，他就已经回来了
By the time you got there, he'd be back here anyway.
进来，快请进
Go on in. Go on in.
对不起
Oh, I'm sorry.
没事的，没事
It's all right. It's all right.
来，路易丝，坐吧
Here. Louise, sit down. Sit down.
我想告诉你事情
I want to tell you something.
这或许有点晚了
It's late, I know.
谢谢你送的围巾
I want to thank you for that scarf.
是的
Oh, yes.
我错看你了
I was wrong about you.
我也是
So was I.
美国石油公司想建立…
The American oil companies are trying to establish
对世界石油的垄断
a world monopoly of oil.
1898年，菲律宾人民推翻 西班牙殖民政府的残酷统治
In 1898, the Filipinos rebelled against the cruel colonial government of Spain.
西班牙人被驱逐后
But after the Spaniards had been driven out...
美国人承认了菲律宾的独立
The Americans have promised the Filipinos independence.
很快宣布菲律宾共和国的成立
Soon an independent Filipino republic will be proclaimed.
美国政府随即派军队去那里驻扎
The government of United States sent soldiers and sailors there...
比英国暴君还专权
...under a dictatorship worse than the British tyrants.
他们这是干嘛？
What's that for?
他们支持你，因为你发起圣战
They are supporting you for your call for a holy war
伊斯兰人民反对西方非信教徒的圣战
of Islamic people against the western infidels.
打搅了，雷德同志
Excuse me, Comrade Reed.
他们说你不满意你演讲的翻译稿
They said you are not happy with the translations of your speech.
我把德语翻成了土耳其语
I did the German into Turkic
奥辛斯基同志把俄语翻译成德语
and Comrade Ossinsky did the Russian into German.
俄语？
Russian?
谁一开始就翻译成了俄语？
Who turned it into Russian in the first place?
我不知道
Well, I don't know.
从兹诺维耶同志办公室拿到的演讲稿…
They were already in Russian when we got them
就是俄语的
from the office of Comrade Zinoviev.
-很抱歉我英语不好 -你的英语不错，同志
- I'm sorry for my English. - Your English is fine, comrade.
兹诺维耶，是你翻译了我的演讲稿吗？
Zinoviev, did you do the translations of my speech?
在我的监督下翻译的
I supervised it. Yes.
我没说圣战，我说的是阶级战争
I didn't say "holy war." I said "class war."
我冒昧修改了一两个短语
I took a liberty of altering a phrase or two.
我不允许别人冒昧修改我的作品
Yes, well, I don't allow people to take those liberties with what I write.
你不知道如何宣传才能感动人吗？
Aren't you propagandist enough to utilize what moves people most?
我要用真相来宣传
I'm propagandist enough to utilize the truth.
谁定义真相？是你还是党？
And who defines this truth? You or the party?
你只需要致力于演讲…
Is your life dedicated to speaking for...
不用你说我要致力于什么！
You don't talk about what my life is dedicated to!
你连这辈子致力于什么事业都还没决定
Your life? You haven't resolved what your life is dedicated to.
你把自己看作艺术家，同时也是革命家
You see yourself as an artist and at the same time as a revolutionary.
看作是你妻子的爱人 也是代表美国阶级的发言人
As a lover to your wife, but also as a spokesman for the American classes.
兹诺维耶，你根本不知道一个人…
Zinoviev, you don't think a man can be an individual
是可以对集体忠诚的
and be true to the collective,
可同时代表自己国家和共产国际说话
or speak for his own country and the International at the same time,
既忠于妻子，依然对革命忠诚
or love his wife and still be faithful to the revolution,
而你根本就没有什么可以奉献！
you don't have a self to give!
你愿意把自己献身给革命吗？
Would you ever be willing to give yourself to this revolution?
当你把一个人和他最爱的东西分开时
When you separate a man from what he loves the most,
你要做的就是净化他的心灵
what you do is purge what's unique in him.
当你净化了他的心灵
And when you purge what's unique in him,
-你就消除了异议 -雷德同志
- you purge dissent. - Comrade Reed.
当你消除了异议，你就扼杀了革命
And when you purge dissent, you kill the revolution!
革命就是异议！
Revolution is dissent!
-雷德同志 -你别重写我写的东西
- Comrade Reed. - You don't rewrite what I write!
是反革命份子
Comrade Reed, counter-revolutionaries!
Counter-revolutionaries, Comrade Reed!
爸爸
Papa!
爸爸！
别离开我
Don't leave me.
请别离开我
Please don't leave me.
同志，医生现在想见你
Comrade, the doctor would like to see you now.
医生觉得还需要进一步分析
The doctor thinks that we must do more analysis.
几天后他的情况会更明朗
And a picture of his illness will be clearer in a few days.
他想要你知道
And he wants you to know
我们会给雷德同志最好的医治
that we shall do the best conditions for Comrade Reed
以防高血压…
to prevent possibility of high blood pressure
引起中风
to cause a stroke.
我真的…我知道…
I really... I know...
什么？
What?
你好吗？
How are you?
不
No.
杰克？
Jack?
我没有…
You know, I don't... I don't...
你听见吗？
You hear it?
什么？
- Huh? - What was that?
水在叮咚响
The water plays little songs.
现在不是12月吗？
It's not December, is it?
天哪
My, my, my, my.
天哪，几点了？
God. What a time it was, huh?
-想跟我去纽约吗？ -纽约？
- Want to come to New York with me? - New York?
有出租车在等我
I got a taxi waiting.
我不介意
I wouldn't mind.
以什么身份？
What as?
什么身份？
不知道
Gee, I don't know.
同志身份？
Comrades?
同志
Comrades.
我想回家
Well, I want to go home.
是的
Yeah.
我去给你倒水
I'll get you some water.
天哪
Oh, God.
那是在下午
It was in the afternoon,
好像是在秋天的时候
sometime in the fall, I think.
好像是10月
October, I think.
有人来告诉我
Somebody came to tell me
杰克・雷德死了
that Jack Reed died.
可以想象…
You can imagine how...
我当时的感受
How I felt.
我把他们全都忘了
I'd forgotten all about them.
他们是社会主义者吗？
Were they socialists?
他们很多人都是理想主义者
Many of them were idealists.
你知道，事情去了又来
You know, things go and come back again.
我不知道外界怎么看他们
I don't know what the outside world thought of them,
但他们是一对夫妇
but they were a couple.
人们总是提起 路易丝・拜伦和杰克・雷德
I mean, you always spoke of Louise Bryant and Jack Reed.
他只是一个普通的年轻人
He was just a man in the prime of life.
我都不知道他们有没有孩子
I don't even know. Did they ever have any children?
可能没有
They probably didn't have any children,
他和路易丝
he and Louise.
有孩子的时候…
Again, you can't tell, when you have children,
他们可能就不会从事革命了
whether they will carry on your revolutionary tradition or not.
他为什么那样做？
Why did he do it?
这就好像在问爱迪生为什么发明…
Well, it's impossible to say
或是高利科奇为何唱歌…
why Edison invented,
永远不会有答案
or why Galli-Curci sang...
他是个热血男儿
He was definitely a stirrer-up of people.
那是他的天地
That was his field.
那就是他要从事的事业
That's what he came to do, apparently.
他出名，但不是很出名
He's well-known amongst a few, but not everybody.
很多人不知道他是谁
They don't know who in heck he is.
我期待自己某天死去
I look for myself to die any day.
列宁问他是不是美国人
He was asked by Lenin, "Are you an American?"
他说是
He said, "Yes."
列宁问是美国人中的美国人吗？
And Lenin said, "An American American?"
雷德说是
And Reed said, "Yes."
当然，没有人想死
Of course, nobody goes with the idea of dying.
每个人都想活着
Everybody wants to live.
我不记得他确切的话语了
I don't remember his exact words,
大意是…
but the meaning was
大事业在前方…
that grand things are ahead,
值得为之生为之死
worth living and worth dying for.
他自己那样说的
He himself said that.